<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="http://www.oasis-open.org/docbook/xml/5.0/rng/docbookxi.rng" schematypens="http://relaxng.org/ns/structure/1.0"?>
<chapter xmlns="http://docbook.org/ns/docbook" 
        xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude"
        xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" version="5.0">
	<title>Related work</title>
	<para>In the real world, economies are complex systems consisting of many autonomous heterogeneous
		interacting agents that exhibit emergent properties at the aggregate level. The recent
		worldwide economic crisis has speeded up the revolution of the methodological foundations of
		macroeconomic theory. The debate has arisen as to the quest for microfoundation concerning
		the microfoundations of macroeconomics. In order to try to explain macroeconomic behavior,
		modern macroeconomics use the microfoundations approach to build aggregate models, typically
		in the form of dynamic stochastic general equilibrium (DSGE) models. Furthermore, these
		models are constructed on the basis of numerous restrictive unrealistic assumptions such as
		homogeneity of individuals, perfect rationlity, rational expectations, perfect ex-ante
		coordination in an equilibrium, etc. Indeed, these assumptions appear inconsistent with real
		world economic operation. However, unfortunately, the mainstream macroeconomics embodied in
		DSGE models was a poor guide to the origins of the economic crisis, and left its followers
		unprepared for the symptoms.</para>
	<para>In recent years another modeling methodology which has emerged at the same time as DSGE
		models is agent-based computational economics (ACE). In fact, In order to investigate and
		understand global regularities in economic processes, different real world issues such as
		asymmetric information, imperfect competition, strategic interaction, collective learning
		and multiple equilibria possibility should be taken into account. The ACE modeling approach
		featured by bounded rationality, endogenous out-of-equilibrium dynamics and direct
		interactions seems well suited to respond to these realities. It is used to study complex
		adaptive systems that are populated by many interacting agents with exogenously given
		behavioral rules. Every agent is defined as an individual actor that has some reasoning and
		decision-making abilities that guide his interaction with others. A major advantage of the
		ACE approach is that assumptions about the macro level are not particularly required. The
		phenomena of the macro level are endogenously emerging from micro assumptions.</para>
	<para>ACE models to macroeconomic studies can be grouped into two categories. The first category
		includes massive simulations of real economies. The EURACE project, as a representative of
		this type, models the European economy. The second category contains stylized models of
		basic economies.</para>
	<para>Matthias Lengnick presents in his work a baseline agent-based macroeconomic model which
		belongs to the second category. The baseline model is defined as a simple minimal ACE model
		which is concerned with basic macroeconomic relations in a non-growth environment. The
		components of the model are only households and firms, both of which are described by
		simple, adaptive rules of behavior. In order to embody the non-growth environment, supposed
		that the number of households and firms is exogenously fixed. The model simulates a pure
		market economy where government and central bank are not considered. The economy has only
		one region where all households and firms are located. In the model, different interactions
		and decisions take place in different time intervals like a day or a month, for example,
		households buy consumption goods daily while recruiting activities of firms are carried out
		per month. In general, the minimal unit of time is a day. Each month is set to have 21
		coherent days.</para>
	<para>Based on activities of households and firms, sum up, the baseline model consists of a
		consumption goods and a labor market. In the consumption goods market, transactions between
		households and firms are taking place daily. Consumption goods are produced by firms and
		sold to households. Different firms produce a homogeneous good. A crucial assumption is that
		households cannot buy consumption goods from any firm, but they are only able to establish
		business relations with 7 different firms, including their respective employer. By contrast,
		firms can have trading relations with any household. However, trading relationships between
		households and firms are unstable and allowed to change during the running of the
		simulation. In the labor market, for producing consumption goods only one input factor is
		used, that is labor, which is provided by the household. Once a firm needs more laborers to
		expand business, it has some vacancies for households. If a household is discontented with
		his present job or unemployed, he looks for a new job.</para>
	<para>In the following the main activities and decision processes of households and firms are
		listed according to the sequence of events.</para>
	<para>At the beginning of a month each firm checks once every month whether any of its
		properties such as the wage rate, the number of employees and the goods price have to be
		adjusted. The dicision whether the wage rate should be changed is based on past hiring
		status at this offered wage rate. The number of employees or the goods price is determined
		based on a comparison of the current stock level with the most recent demand. After that,
		households begin to find more beneficial trading partners in order that new partners can
		provide cheaper consumption goods than existing ones or satisfy the demand fully. If they
		find such a partner, the existing connection is removed and the new one is established. If a
		household is unemployed, he needs to look for a job. If a firm has vacancy and its offered
		wage rate is at least as high as the reservation wage of the household, the position is
		accepted. Otherwise, the household keeps searching for work. In another case, an employed
		household may consider changing jobs, if his current wage is less than reservation wage.
		Moreover, a household also has to decide about the budget that is spent for consumption and
		consequently determine how much to save.</para>
	<para>After the above events have been performed, households purchase consumption goods from
		their trading partners every day. Each household visits randomly one of his partners for
		consumption every time. If the inventories of the firm are high enough to satisfy his daily
		demand, the household buys consumption goods he needs. In the opposite case, the household
		has to visit randomly another trading partner to satisfy the remaining demand. Next, each
		firm produces consumption goods every day in order to replenish inventories in time.</para>
	<para>At the end of a month wages are paid to all workers. At the same time, the liquidity of
		the employer is reduced while the liquidity of each worker is raised. In cases of positive
		remaining liquidity, the firm pays dividends to all households. In some cases the firm has
		negative liquidity, because there are no banks in the model, supposed that households are
		required to pay the firm deficit. After that, households change their reservation wage based
		on their currently received labor income.</para>
	<para>In this paper, another ACE model [dawid2009] which is chosen for reconstruction belongs to
		the first category. This model is part of the EURACE project. In contrast with the baseline
		model, the model of dawid2009 is more complicated. It can be regarded as the expansion of
		the baseline model. More specifically, the baseline model contains only two types of agents
		such as households and firms while the model of dawid2009 has four types of agents like
		households, consumption goods producers (this type of agent is equivalent to firm agent of
		the baseline model), malls and capital goods producer. Mall is a local market platform and
		capital goods producer provides investment goods that are used by consumption goods
		producers to produce consumption goods together with labor. However, in the baseline model
		investment goods are not taken into account, of course, no investment goods market. The
		model of dawid2009 consists of an investment goods, a consumption goods and a labor market.
		In the baseline model, the economy has only one region. The model of dawid2009 describes a
		complex economy that consists of two regions for policy experiments.</para>
	<para>There are several advantages to the baseline model. First, although the model is simple, it
		can already mimic a number of empirical facts. Second, the model follows the ACE approach
		rigorously. Third, this model, of course, can be modified to explore other research
		areas.</para>
	<para>At the same time, the baseline model also has some disadvantages. First, the model based on a
		non-growth environment cannot reflect economies in the real world. Second, it is unrealistic
		that the number of households and firms is fixed throughout the simulation. Third, in the
		model, there exist several restrictive unrealistic assumptions.</para>
	<para>The model of dawid2009 is a relatively complete model. It tries to overcome unrealistic
		assumptions and mimic real economies. Its practicality and applicability are all
		strong.</para>
</chapter>
