<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="http://www.oasis-open.org/docbook/xml/5.0/rng/docbookxi.rng" schematypens="http://relaxng.org/ns/structure/1.0"?>
<chapter xmlns="http://docbook.org/ns/docbook" 
        xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude"
        xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" version="5.0">
	<title>Simulation results</title>
	<para>This chapter shows the simulation results with the help of graphical statistics which appear
		at simulation runtime on the panel in AOR simulator. In the simulation presented here there
		are six scenarios, each of which corresponds to one set of simulation results. In order to
		confirm that the model has been reconstructed successfully, the results will be compared
		with those of the original model. But it is worth note that because of some deficiency of
		the original model, for example, there exist some fuzzy rules, these uncertain factors will
		cause that the reconstructed results can deviate from the actual results of the original
		model.</para>
	<para>In the paper of the original model, the low-high scenario is taken as an example to publish
		the simulation results. In view of this situation, the reconstructed results for that
		scenario even taking into account costs from commuting are also shown.</para>
	<figure>
		<title>Runs for zero (left panel) and low (0.05) (right panel) commuting costs; total
			outputs (solid line), output in the low skill region (dotted line), output in the high
			skill region (dashed line)</title>
		<mediaobject>
			<imageobject>
				<imagedata fileref="png/total%20outputs.png"/>
			</imageobject>
		</mediaobject>
	</figure>
	<para>Figure 6.1 shows the dynamics of the aggregate output of CGPs in the low skill region and the
		high skill region. In the low-high scenario, in case of no commuting costs both regions
		produce about the same amount. Whereas with low (0.05) commuting costs the output of the
		high skill region is larger than that of the low skill region. Clearly, CGPs in the high
		skill region take advantage of the more skilled workforce which could lead to increased
		production to a larger degree than CGPs in the low region.</para>
	<figure>
		<title>Output from the AOR model</title>
		<mediaobject>
			<imageobject>
				<imagedata fileref="png/output%20AOR.png"/>
			</imageobject>
		</mediaobject>
	</figure>
	<para>As can be seen in figure 6.2 output in the high skill region is larger than that in the low
		skill region. Compared with figure 6.1, the shape of the curve is relative smooth. The main
		reason of the results difference between figure 6.1 and figure 6.2 is that the estimated
		demand distribution is not clearly spelled out in the original model and instead a uniform
		distribution is used in the reconstructed model. Because the output of a CGP is depends on
		its planned output at every period. However, the planned output is based on the optimal
		stock level, which is obtained by using the estimated demand distribution. So the choice of
		different types of estimated demand distribution makes the results deviate.</para>
	<figure>
		<title>Runs for zero (left panel) and low (0.05) (right panel) commuting costs; number of
			commuters from low to high skill region (dotted line), number of commuters from high to
			low skill region (dashed line)</title>
		<mediaobject>
			<imageobject>
				<imagedata fileref="png/number%20of%20commuters.png"/>
			</imageobject>
		</mediaobject>
	</figure>
	<para>The both panels give insight into a large number of high skill workers from the high skill
		region commute to the low skill region. In case of no commuting costs there is a large
		number of commuters from the low skill to the high skill region. In the opposite case, the
		flow from the low skill to the high skill region becomes very small.</para>
	<figure>
		<title>Number of commuters from the AOR model</title>
		<mediaobject>
			<imageobject>
				<imagedata fileref="png/number%20of%20commuters%20AOR.png"/>
			</imageobject>
		</mediaobject>
	</figure>
	<para>The result of figure 6.4 is similar to that of figure 6.3. Both of figures indicate that on
		the one hand, a large number of workers still work from the high skill region to the low
		skill region, though there exist commuting costs. On the other hand, in case of commuting
		costs, the number of workers from the low skill region to the high skill region becomes
		fewer and fewer. If there exist commuting costs, in fact, workers do not want to work across
		the region no matter which region they live in. However, in the high skill region the factor
		productivity is high. As a result, CGPs need relatively fewer workers. Many workers with
		high skill lose jobs. They must turn to the low skill region and work for producers that
		locate there. In the low skill region it has the opposite conditions. The factor
		productivity in that place is low. CGPs there need more workers. So a large proportion of
		workers in the low skill region just stay where they are.</para>
	<figure>
		<title>Runs for zero (left panel) and low (0.05) (right panel) commuting costs; prices in
			the low skill region (dashed line), prices in the high skill region (dotted
			line)</title>
		<mediaobject>
			<imageobject>
				<imagedata fileref="png/prices.png"/>
			</imageobject>
		</mediaobject>
	</figure>
	<para>In the low-high scenario, there is no much difference in price between the goods produced in
		the two regions.</para>
	<figure>
		<title>Prices from the AOR model</title>
		<mediaobject>
			<imageobject>
				<imagedata fileref="png/prices%20AOR.png"/>
			</imageobject>
		</mediaobject>
	</figure>
	<para>The result in figure 6.6 is similar to that in figure 6.5, but the trends of curves in the
		two figures have a little difference from each other. The both figures show that the
		differences of the prices are small in the high skill region and in the low skill region. In
		both regions the wage differences driven the price differences, and there are no systematic
		wage differences in both regions in a global labor market. So the price difference in the
		two regions is not so much. The prices of goods are triggered by the costs of goods, which
		depend on the planned output. As mentioned ini figure 6.1 and 6.2, the output in figure 6.2
		is not the same as that in figure 6.1. Obviously, the results of the two figures have
		difference.</para>
	<figure>
		<title>Runs for zero (left panel) and low (0.05) (right panel) commuting costs; total labor
			income of workers in the low skill region (dashed line) and the high skill region
			(dotted line)</title>
		<mediaobject>
			<imageobject>
				<imagedata fileref="png/total%20labor%20income%20of%20workers.png"/>
			</imageobject>
		</mediaobject>
	</figure>
	<para>In both scenarios the total labor income of workers is larger in the high skill region than
		in the low skill region. This is because high-skilled workers earn higher wages than
		low-skilled ones. In case of low (0.05) commuting costs the difference is smaller.</para>
	<figure>
		<title>Total labor income of workers from the AOR model</title>
		<mediaobject>
			<imageobject>
				<imagedata fileref="png/total%20labor%20income%20of%20workers%20AOR.png"/>
			</imageobject>
		</mediaobject>
	</figure>
	<para/>
	<para>Compared with figure 6.7, it is shown that results are in agreement with the original
		results. They both show that labor income in the high skill region is larger than that in
		the low skill region. But as can be seen in figure 6.8, the difference of the total labor
		income between the high skill region and the low skill region is larger than that in figure
		6.7. The reason is that in the reconstructed model a relative higher wage level for workers
		is defined. If taken commuting costs into consideration, then the labor income of workers is
		after deducting commuting costs. Therefore, commuting costs are in smaller amounts than
		those in the original model. So results in this point are a little different from the
		original results.</para>
</chapter>
