<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="http://www.oasis-open.org/docbook/xml/5.0/rng/docbookxi.rng" schematypens="http://relaxng.org/ns/structure/1.0"?>
<chapter xmlns="http://docbook.org/ns/docbook" 
        xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude"
        xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" version="5.0">
	<title>Simulation results</title>
	<para>This chapter shows the simulation results with the help of graphical statistics which appear
		at simulation runtime on the panel in AOR simulator. In the simulation presented here there
		are six scenarios, each of which corresponds to one set of simulation results. In order to
		confirm that the model has been reconstructed successfully, the results will be compared
		with those of the original model. But it is worth note that because of some deficiency of
		the original model, for example, there exist some fuzzy rules, these uncertain factors will
		cause that the reconstructed results can deviate from the actual results of the original
		model.</para>
	<para>In the paper of the original model, the low-high scenario is taken as an example to publish
		the simulation results. In view of this situation, the reconstructed results for that
		scenario even taking into account costs from commuting are also shown.</para>
	<figure>
		<title>Runs for zero (left panel) and low (0.05) (right panel) commuting costs; total
			outputs (solid line), output in the low skill region (dotted line), output in the high
			skill region (dashed line)</title>
		<mediaobject>
			<imageobject>
				<imagedata fileref="png/total%20outputs.png"/>
			</imageobject>
		</mediaobject>
	</figure>
	<para>In the low-high scenario, in case of no commuting costs both regions produce about the
		same amount. Whereas with low (0.05) commuting costs the output of the high skill region is
		larger than that of the low skill region. Clearly, CGPs in the high skill region take
		advantage of the more skilled workforce which could lead to increased production to a larger
		degree than CGPs in the low region.</para>
	<figure>
		<title>Output from the AOR model</title>
		<mediaobject>
			<imageobject>
				<imagedata fileref="png/output%20AOR.png"/>
			</imageobject>
		</mediaobject>
	</figure>
	<figure>
		<title>Runs for zero (left panel) and low (0.05) (right panel) commuting costs; number of
			commuters from low to high skill region (dotted line), number of commuters from high to
			low skill region (dashed line)</title>
		<mediaobject>
			<imageobject>
				<imagedata fileref="png/number%20of%20commuters.png"/>
			</imageobject>
		</mediaobject>
	</figure>
	<para>The both panels give insight into a large number of high skill workers from the high skill
		region commute to the low skill region. In case of no commuting costs there is a large
		number of commuters from the low skill to the high skill region. In the opposite case, the
		flow from the low skill to the high skill region becomes very small.</para>
	<figure>
		<title>Number of commuters from the AOR model</title>
		<mediaobject>
			<imageobject>
				<imagedata fileref="png/number%20of%20commuters%20AOR.png"/>
			</imageobject>
		</mediaobject>
	</figure>
	<figure>
		<title>Runs for zero (left panel) and low (0.05) (right panel) commuting costs; prices in
			the low skill region (dashed line), prices in the high skill region (dotted
			line)</title>
		<mediaobject>
			<imageobject>
				<imagedata fileref="png/prices.png"/>
			</imageobject>
		</mediaobject>
	</figure>
	<para>In the low-high scenario, there is not much difference in price between the goods produced
		in the two regions.</para>
	<figure>
		<title>Prices from the AOR model</title>
		<mediaobject>
			<imageobject>
				<imagedata fileref="png/prices%20AOR.png"/>
			</imageobject>
		</mediaobject>
	</figure>
	<figure>
		<title>Runs for zero (left panel) and low (0.05) (right panel) commuting costs; total labor
			income of workers in the low skill region (dashed line) and the high skill region
			(dotted line)</title>
		<mediaobject>
			<imageobject>
				<imagedata fileref="png/total%20labor%20income%20of%20workers.png"/>
			</imageobject>
		</mediaobject>
	</figure>
	<para>In both scenarios the total labor income of workers is larger in the high skill region
		than in the low skill region. In case of low (0.05) commuting costs the difference is
		smaller.</para>
	<figure>
		<title>Total labor income of workers from the AOR model</title>
		<mediaobject>
			<imageobject>
				<imagedata fileref="png/total%20labor%20income%20of%20workers%20AOR.png"/>
			</imageobject>
		</mediaobject>
	</figure>
</chapter>
