<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="http://www.oasis-open.org/docbook/xml/5.0/rng/docbookxi.rng" schematypens="http://relaxng.org/ns/structure/1.0"?>
<chapter xmlns="http://docbook.org/ns/docbook" 
        xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude"
        xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" version="5.0">
	<title>Simulation results</title>
	<para>This chapter shows the simulation results with the help of graphical statistics which appear
		at simulation runtime on the panel in AOR simulator. In the simulation presented here there
		are six scenarios, each of which corresponds to one set of simulation results. In order to
		confirm that the model has been reconstructed successfully, the results will be compared
		with those of the original model. But it is worth note that because of some deficiency of
		the original model, for example, there exist some fuzzy rules, these uncertain factors will
		cause that the reconstructed results can deviate from the actual results of the original
		model.</para>
	<para>In the paper of the original model, the low-high scenario is taken as an example to publish
		the simulation results. In view of this situation, the reconstructed results for that
		scenario even taking into account costs from commuting are also shown.</para>
	<figure>
		<title>Runs for zero (left panel) and low (0.05) (right panel) commuting costs; total outputs
			(solid line), output in the low skill region (dashed line), output in the high skill
			region (dotted line) <citation>Dawid2009</citation></title>
		<mediaobject>
			<imageobject>
				<imagedata fileref="png/total%20outputs.png"/>
			</imageobject>
		</mediaobject>
	</figure>
	<para>Figure 6.1 shows the dynamics of the aggregate output of CGPs in the low skill region and the
		high skill region. In the low-high scenario, in case of no commuting costs both regions
		produce about the same amount. Whereas with low (0.05) commuting costs the output of the
		high skill region is not larger than that of the low skill region.</para>
	<figure>
		<title>Output for zero commuting costs from the AOR model</title>
		<mediaobject>
			<imageobject>
				<imagedata fileref="png/output%20AOR%20(zero).png"/>
			</imageobject>
		</mediaobject>
	</figure>
	<figure>
		<title>Output for low (0.05) commuting costs from the AOR model</title>
		<mediaobject>
			<imageobject>
				<imagedata fileref="png/output%20AOR.png"/>
			</imageobject>
		</mediaobject>
	</figure>
	<para>As can be seen in figure 6.2 and figure 6.3, the results show the dynamics of the aggregate
		output of CGPs from the AOR model. It is shown that both regions produce the same output, if
		there are no commuting costs. In case of low commuting costs, the result indicates that the
		output of the high skill region is larger than that of the low skill region. This result is
		completely contrary to the original one. As can be seen in the right panel of figure 6.1, it
		is shown that the output of the high skill region is lower than that of the low skill
		region. For this result the authors of the original model gave such an explanation: "To
		understand why the output of the high skill region is not larger than that of the low skill
		region, it has to be kept in mind that the terms high and low skill regions refers to the
		skills of the workers living in a certain region rather than to the skills of workers
		working in a certain region." <citation>Dawid2009</citation> The explanation is farfetched
		and unclear. This result is argued for four reasons: firstly, the workers with relatively
		higher skills in the high skill region have more income than the workers in the low skill
		region. Accordingly, the high skill region has a higher level of consumption. So the output
		should be larger. Secondly, the workers in the high skill region have higher specific
		skills, which determine the higher level of production that drives the higher output.
		Thirdly, in the real world, it is impossible that the output in the high skill region is
		lower than that in the low skill region. Finally, this is also the most important reason. It
		is strange that the authors of the original model showed in another article
			<citation>Dawid2008</citation> about the same model the contrary result, which agrees
		with the result of figure 6.3.</para>
	<figure>
		<title>Runs for zero (left panel) and low (0.05) (right panel) commuting costs; number of
			commuters from low to high skill region (dotted line), number of commuters from high to
			low skill region (dashed line) <citation>Dawid2009</citation></title>
		<mediaobject>
			<imageobject>
				<imagedata fileref="png/number%20of%20commuters.png"/>
			</imageobject>
		</mediaobject>
	</figure>
	<para>The both panels give insight into a large number of high skill workers from the high skill
		region commute to the low skill region. In case of no commuting costs there is a large
		number of commuters from the low skill to the high skill region. In the opposite case, the
		flow from the low skill to the high skill region becomes very small.</para>
	<figure>
		<title>Number of commuters for zero commuting costs from the AOR model</title>
		<mediaobject>
			<imageobject>
				<imagedata fileref="png/number%20of%20commuters%20AOR%20(zero).png"/>
			</imageobject>
		</mediaobject>
	</figure>
	<figure>
		<title>Number of commuters for low (0.05) commuting costs from the AOR model</title>
		<mediaobject>
			<imageobject>
				<imagedata fileref="png/number%20of%20commuters%20AOR.png"/>
			</imageobject>
		</mediaobject>
	</figure>
	<para>Compared with figure 6.4, the results of figure 6.5 and figure 6.6 are all similar to the
		original results. Both of figures indicate that in case of no commuting costs, there are a
		large number of commuters from the high skill region to the low skill region. In case of low
		commuting costs, on the one hand, a large number of workers still work from the high skill
		region to the low skill region, though there exist commuting costs. On the other hand, the
		number of workers from the low skill region to the high skill region becomes fewer and
		fewer. If there exist commuting costs, in fact, workers do not want to work across the
		region no matter which region they live in. However, in the high skill region the factor
		productivity is high. As a result, CGPs need relatively fewer workers. Many workers with
		high skill lose jobs. They must turn to the low skill region and work for producers that
		locate there. In the low skill region it has the opposite conditions. The factor
		productivity in that place is low. CGPs there need more workers. So a large proportion of
		workers in the low skill region just stay where they are.</para>
	<figure>
		<title>Runs for zero (left panel) and low (0.05) (right panel) commuting costs; prices in the low
			skill region (dashed line), prices in the high skill region (dotted line)
				<citation>Dawid2009</citation></title>
		<mediaobject>
			<imageobject>
				<imagedata fileref="png/prices.png"/>
			</imageobject>
		</mediaobject>
	</figure>
	<para>In the low-high scenario, there is no much difference in price between the goods produced in
		the two regions.</para>
	<figure>
		<title>Prices for zero commuting costs from the AOR model</title>
		<mediaobject>
			<imageobject>
				<imagedata fileref="png/prices%20AOR%20(zero).png"/>
			</imageobject>
		</mediaobject>
	</figure>
	<figure>
		<title>Prices for low (0.05) commuting costs from the AOR model</title>
		<mediaobject>
			<imageobject>
				<imagedata fileref="png/prices%20AOR.png"/>
			</imageobject>
		</mediaobject>
	</figure>
	<para>Compared with figure 6.7, the results in figure 6.8 and figure 6.9 are all similar to the
		original results, no matter if there exist commuting costs or not. But the trends of curves
		in the two figures have a little difference from each other. The both figures show that the
		differences of the prices are small in the high skill region and in the low skill region. In
		both regions the wage differences driven the price differences, and there are no systematic
		wage differences in both regions in a global labor market. So the price difference in the
		two regions is not so much. The prices of goods are triggered by the costs of goods, which
		depend on the planned output. However, the planned output is based on the optimal stock
		level, which is obtained by using the estimated demand distribution. So the choice of
		different estimated demand distribution functions makes the results deviate.</para>
	<figure>
		<title>Runs for zero (left panel) and low (0.05) (right panel) commuting costs; total labor income
			of workers in the low skill region (dashed line) and the high skill region (dotted line)
				<citation>Dawid2009</citation></title>
		<mediaobject>
			<imageobject>
				<imagedata fileref="png/total%20labor%20income%20of%20workers.png"/>
			</imageobject>
		</mediaobject>
	</figure>
	<para>In both scenarios the total labor income of workers is larger in the high skill region than
		in the low skill region. This is because high-skilled workers earn higher wages than
		low-skilled ones. In case of low (0.05) commuting costs the difference is smaller.</para>
	<figure>
		<title>Total labor income of workers for zero commuting costs from the AOR model</title>
		<mediaobject>
			<imageobject>
				<imagedata fileref="png/total%20labor%20income%20of%20workers%20AOR%20(zero).png"/>
			</imageobject>
		</mediaobject>
	</figure>
	<figure>
		<title>Total labor income of workers for low (0.05) commuting costs from the AOR model</title>
		<mediaobject>
			<imageobject>
				<imagedata fileref="png/total%20labor%20income%20of%20workers%20AOR.png"/>
			</imageobject>
		</mediaobject>
	</figure>
	<para>Compared with figure 6.10, it is shown that reconstructed results are in agreement with the
		original results. They all show that labor income in the high skill region is larger than
		that in the low skill region. But as can be seen in figure 6.12, the difference of the total
		labor income between the high skill region and the low skill region is larger than that in
		the right panel of figure 6.10. The reason is that in the reconstructed model a relative
		higher wage level for workers is defined. If taken commuting costs into consideration, then
		the labor income of workers is after deducting commuting costs. Therefore, commuting costs
		are in smaller amounts than those in the original model. So results in this point are a
		little different from the original results.</para>
</chapter>
