<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="http://www.oasis-open.org/docbook/xml/5.0/rng/docbookxi.rng" schematypens="http://relaxng.org/ns/structure/1.0"?>
<chapter xmlns="http://docbook.org/ns/docbook" 
        xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude"
        xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" version="5.0">
	<title>The model</title>
	<para>The agent-based macroeconomic model was developed by Herbert Dawid, Simon Gemkow, Philipp
		Harting and Michael Neugart and has been implemented in the Flexible Large-Scale Agent
		Modeling Environment (FLAME) developed by Simon Coakley, Mike Holcombe and others at the
		University of Sheffield (see <link xlink:href="http://www.flame.ac.uk"
			>http://www.flame.ac.uk</link> for more information and references). This part gives an
		overview of the model.</para>
	<section>
		<title>Background to the model</title>
		<para>The model was developed as part of a larger simulation platform for European policymaking
			known as EURACE. EURACE is a major project aiming at creating a complete agent-based
			model of the European economy for evaluating European economic policies. The three-years
			EURACE project started in September 2006. It involves economists and computer scientists
			from eight research centres in Germany, France, Italy, the UK, and Turkey, as well as
			the 2001 Nobel laureate in economics, Joseph Stiglitz. The EURACE model has a distinct
			spatial structure simulating the regional statistical units used by Eurostat. It
			contains various (typically, regional) artificial markets for real commodities (that is,
			consumption goods, investment goods and labor) and markets for financial assets (such as
			loans, bonds and stocks). For a general overview of the EURACE model, see <link
				xlink:href="http://www.eurace.org">http://www.eurace.org</link>.</para>
		<para>The model is a simplified version based on EURACE's labor market module. Its structure can
			be seen as follows.</para>
		<figure>
			<title>Model Structure</title>
			<mediaobject>
				<imageobject>
					<imagedata fileref="png/model%20structure.png"/>
				</imageobject>
			</mediaobject>
		</figure>
		<para>The main purpose of the model is to investigate how the spatial skill distribution in the
			absence of policy intervention influences the speed of technological change, the flow of
			labor force and the growth of wage level in an economy. Therefore, policy implications
			aiming at the change of local skill distribution play an important role in the model. In
			order to capture the effects of different spatial distributions of policy measures, the
			economy is divided into two regions. According to general skill levels of workers a
			region can be declared as one of three possible types: low skill region, medium skill
			region or high skill region. More specifically, there are five general skill levels 1 to
			5, where 1 is the lowest skill level and 5 is the level with the highest skill. In a low
			skill region the skill distribution is such that 80% of workers have the lowest general
			skill level, whereas the remaining workers are equally distributed across the other four
			levels of general skills. Analogously, a region is a medium skill or high skill region
			if 80% of workers have general skill level 3 respectively 5.</para>
		<table frame="all">
			<title>General skill distributions in the three different types of regions</title>
			<tgroup cols="6" align="center">
				<colspec colname="c1" colnum="1" colwidth="1.0*"/>
				<colspec colname="c2" colnum="2" colwidth="1.0*"/>
				<colspec colname="c3" colnum="3" colwidth="1.0*"/>
				<colspec colname="c4" colnum="4" colwidth="1.0*"/>
				<colspec colname="c5" colnum="5" colwidth="1.0*"/>
				<colspec colname="c6" colnum="6" colwidth="1.0*"/>
				<thead valign="middle">
					<row>
						<entry>Region type</entry>
						<entry>Level 1</entry>
						<entry>Level 2</entry>
						<entry>Level 3</entry>
						<entry>Level 4</entry>
						<entry>Level 5</entry>
					</row>
				</thead>
				<tbody valign="middle">
					<row>
						<entry>Low skill</entry>
						<entry>80%</entry>
						<entry>5%</entry>
						<entry>5%</entry>
						<entry>5%</entry>
						<entry>5%</entry>
					</row>
					<row>
						<entry>Medium skill</entry>
						<entry>5%</entry>
						<entry>5%</entry>
						<entry>80%</entry>
						<entry>5%</entry>
						<entry>5%</entry>
					</row>
					<row>
						<entry>High skill</entry>
						<entry>5%</entry>
						<entry>5%</entry>
						<entry>5%</entry>
						<entry>5%</entry>
						<entry>80%</entry>
					</row>
				</tbody>
			</tgroup>
		</table>
		<para>In this model, both regions are initially set to low skill regions. A policy maker
			intends to improve the regional skill distributions. To that end, there are two options
			here. Either both regions are upgraded to medium skill or all efforts are concentrated
			in one region thereby moving this region to high skill whereas the skill distribution in
			another region stays unchanged. Finally, the effects of different policy types can be
			compared.</para>
	</section>
	<section>
		<title>General description</title>
		<para>The model describes an economy that contains an investment (or capital) goods, a consumption
			goods and a labor market. There exists a single type of product in each market, i.e.,
			investment goods are supplied in the investment goods market, consumption goods are sold
			at malls in the consumption goods market and labor is considered as a commodity in the
			labor market. The economy is populated with a large number of agents, which are
			summarized as two types of active agents and two types of passive agents in the sense
			that active agents can take decisions, whereas passive ones can not. Each type of agent
			can have different roles corresponding to its activities in the markets. The following
			summarizes these roles.</para>
		<table frame="all">
			<title>Agent types and their market roles</title>
			<tgroup cols="4" align="center">
				<colspec colname="c1" colnum="1" colwidth="1.0*"/>
				<colspec colname="c2" colnum="2" colwidth="1.0*"/>
				<colspec colname="c3" colnum="3" colwidth="1.0*"/>
				<colspec colname="c4" colnum="4" colwidth="1.0*"/>
				<thead valign="middle">
					<row>
						<entry>Agent</entry>
						<entry>Type</entry>
						<entry>Market</entry>
						<entry>Role</entry>
					</row>
				</thead>
				<tbody valign="middle">
					<row>
						<entry morerows="1">Household</entry>
						<entry morerows="1">Active</entry>
						<entry>Comsumption Goods Market</entry>
						<entry>Buyer</entry>
					</row>
					<row>
						<entry>Labor Market</entry>
						<entry>Worker</entry>
					</row>
					<row>
						<entry morerows="2">Consumption Goods Producer (henceforth called CGP)</entry>
						<entry morerows="2">Active</entry>
						<entry>Investment Goods Market</entry>
						<entry>Buyer</entry>
					</row>
					<row>
						<entry>Consumption Goods Market</entry>
						<entry>Seller</entry>
					</row>
					<row>
						<entry>Labor Market</entry>
						<entry>Employer</entry>
					</row>
					<row>
						<entry>Mall</entry>
						<entry>Passive</entry>
						<entry>Consumption Goods Market</entry>
						<entry>Information transfer between consumption goods producers and
							households</entry>
					</row>
					<row>
						<entry>Capital Goods Producer (henceforth called IGP)</entry>
						<entry>Passive</entry>
						<entry>Investment Goods Market</entry>
						<entry>Seller</entry>
					</row>
				</tbody>
			</tgroup>
		</table>
		<section>
			<title>Markets and agents</title>
			<para>Agents acting within markets are distributed across regions where the consumption goods
				market is local, the other markets are global.</para>
			<para>The main actors in the investment goods market are IGP and CGPs. The investment
				goods market is global meaning that CGPs in both regions buy investment goods from
				the unique IGP. Investment goods are offered with infinite supply at an exogenously
				given price and there exists only one type of investment goods. The quality and
				price of supplied investment goods increase randomly over time. The amounts paid for
				investment goods are channeled back into the economy.</para>
			<para>CGPs, households and malls take part in the consumption goods market. Together with labor,
				investment goods are used by CGPs to produce consumption goods. These goods are sold
				at malls to households. Malls are seen as the non-profit local market platforms. On
				the consumption goods market CGPs act globally in the sense that all CGPs store and
				offer their products at every regional mall, but households act locally because
				every household comes to the mall in his region to buy goods at posted prices. CGPs
				receive revenues from the sales. Their income is used to remunerate households in
				order to close the model.</para>
			<para>CGPs and households play in the labor market. A search-and-matching process is used to
				represent the interaction between CGPs and households in this market. The CGP needs
				more laborers in order to expand its production scale. For this reason, it offers
				job vacancies based on the planned output. The household who is job seeker looks for
				a suitable position based on the corresponding salaries of these vacancies. Job
				seekers can apply for jobs in any region, but one thing must be pointed out, that
				is, working outside of their own region is associated with commuting costs which
				have to be subtracted form the wage. Thus, the labor market is global with spatial
				frictions determined by commuting costs.</para>
		</section>
	</section>
</chapter>
