<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?oxygen RNGSchema="http://www.oasis-open.org/docbook/xml/5.0/rng/docbook.rng" type="xml"?>
<article xmlns="http://docbook.org/ns/docbook"
    xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" version="5.0">
	<info>
		<title>Reconstruction of an Agent-Based Simulation Model about Labor Market Policies</title>
		<subtitle>Master Thesis</subtitle>
		<author>
			<personname><firstname>Xi</firstname><surname>Niu</surname></personname>
			<personblurb>
				<simpara>Matrikel-Nr.: 2612390</simpara>
			</personblurb>
			<personblurb>
				<simpara>Betreuer: Prof. Dr. Gerd Wagner</simpara>
			</personblurb>
		</author>
		<copyright>
			<year>2011</year>
			<holder>Brandenburg University of Technology at Cottbus, Chair of Internet Technology</holder>
		</copyright>
		<abstract xml:lang="en">
			<para>In this master thesis an agent-based macroeconomic model used for economic policy
				experiments featuring a distinct geographical dimension and heterogeneous workers with
				respect to skill types is to be introduced and reconstructed with the help of the AOR
				simulation technology that was developed by the Chair of Internet Technology.</para>
		</abstract>
		<abstract xml:lang="de">
			<para>In dieser Masterarbeit wird ein agenten-basiertes makroökonomisches Modell für die
				wirtschaftspolitischen Experimente mit einem eigenen geographischen Dimension und
				heterogenen Arbeitnehmern in Bezug auf Skill-Typen vorgestellt und mit Hilfe der am
				Lehrstuhl Internet-Technologie entwickelten AOR-Simulationstechnologie rekonstruiert.</para>
		</abstract>
	</info>
	<acknowledgements>
		<para>I would like to express my sincere thanks to Prof. Dr. Gerd Wagner for his invaluable
			guidance and advice throughout the course of this thesis. Without his help this paper would
			not be possible.</para>
	</acknowledgements>
	<sect1>
		<title>Introduction</title>
		<para>So far agent-based modeling (ABM) is a powerful simulation modeling technique that has been
			extensively developed and well used in a lot of areas, because it can provide many effective
			methods to facilitate the research into the complex problems of different scientific fields.
			The model which will be in this paper described aims to use ABM to explore the fields of
			economics to analyse the effects of different spatial concentrations of economic policy
			measures depend on spatial frictions in the labor market. The purpose of this paper is to
			remodel it as a multi-agent based simulation using the Agent-Object-Relationship (AOR)
			simulation technology that was developed by Prof. Dr. Gerd Wagner and other team members at
			the Brandenburg University of Technology.</para>
		<para>The paper is organized as follows. In Section 2 the economic model will be introduced.
			Section 3 describes the principles of AOR modeling and simulation in which the model will be
			implemented. Section 4 provides some simulation results, and Section 5 concludes.</para>
	</sect1>
	<sect1>
		<title>The economic model</title>
		<para>The model was developed by Herbert Dawid, Simon Gemkow, Philipp Harting and Michael Neugart
			and has been implemented in the Flexible Large-Scale Agent Modeling Environment (FLAME)
			developed by Simon Coakley, Mike Holcombe and others at the University of Sheffield (see <link
				xlink:href="http://www.flame.ac.uk">http://www.flame.ac.uk</link> for more information and
			references). It is an agent-based macroeconomic model. Its main purpose is to investigate how
			the spatial skill distribution in the absence of policy intervention influences the speed of
			technological change, the flow of labor force and the growth of wage level.</para>
		<sect2>
			<title>Background to the model</title>
			<para>The model was developed as part of a larger simulation platform for European policymaking
				known as EURACE. EURACE is a major project aiming at creating a complete agent-based model
				of the European economy for evaluating European economic policies. The EURACE model has a
				distinct spatial structure simulating the regional statistical units used by Eurostat. It
				contains various (typically, regional) artificial markets for real commodities (that is,
				consumption goods, investment goods and labor) and markets for financial assets (such as
				loans, bonds and stocks). For a general overview of the EURACE model, see <link
					xlink:href="http://www.eurace.org">http://www.eurace.org</link>.</para>
		</sect2>
		<sect2>
			<title>General description</title>
			<para>The model is a simplified version based on EURACE's labor market module. It describes an
				economy that contains three markets namely an investment (or capital) goods, a consumption
				goods and a labor market in a regional context. The main components of the model are agents,
				which are the main body of these markets. In this model there are two types of active agents
				and two types of passive agents in the sense that active agents can take decisions, whereas
				passive ones can not. Each type of agent has one or several `roles' corresponding to its
				activities in the markets. The following summarizes these roles.</para>
			<para>Active Agents:<itemizedlist>
					<listitem>
						<para>Households<itemizedlist>
								<listitem>
									<para>Comsumption Goods Market: Role of Buyer</para>
								</listitem>
								<listitem>
									<para>Labor Market: Role of Worker</para>
								</listitem>
							</itemizedlist></para>
					</listitem>
					<listitem>
						<para>Consumption Goods Producer (henceforth called CGP)<itemizedlist>
								<listitem>
									<para>Investment Goods Market: Role of Buyer</para>
								</listitem>
								<listitem>
									<para>Consumption Goods Market: Role of Seller</para>
								</listitem>
								<listitem>
									<para>Labor Market: Role of Employer</para>
								</listitem>
							</itemizedlist></para>
					</listitem>
				</itemizedlist></para>
			<para>Passive Agents:<itemizedlist>
					<listitem>
						<para>Malls<itemizedlist>
								<listitem>
									<para>Consumption Goods Market: Information Transfer between Consumption Goods
										Producers and Households</para>
								</listitem>
							</itemizedlist></para>
					</listitem>
					<listitem>
						<para>Capital Goods Producer (henceforth called IGP)<itemizedlist>
								<listitem>
									<para>Investment Goods Market: Role of Seller</para>
								</listitem>
							</itemizedlist></para>
					</listitem>
				</itemizedlist></para>
			<para>Agents are distributed over <emphasis role="italic">R = 2</emphasis> regions where the
				consumption goods market is local, the other two markets are global. The minimal time unit
				in the model is a day, but some actions occur on weekly or monthly basis.</para>
			<para>The main actors in the investment goods market are IGP and CGPs. The investment goods
				market is global meaning that CGPs in both regions buy investment goods from the unique IGP.
				Investment goods are offered with infinite supply at an exogenously given price and there
				exists only one type of investment goods. The quality and price of supplied investment goods
				increase randomly over time.</para>
			<para>CGPs, Households and Malls take part in the consumption goods market. Consumption goods are
				sold at malls. Malls are seen as the non-profit local market platforms. On the consumption
				goods market CGPs act globally in the sense that all CGPs store and offer their products at
				every regional mall, but households act locally because every household comes to the mall in
				his region to buy goods at posted prices.</para>
			<para>CGPs and Households play in the labor market. The CGP needs more laborers in order to
				expand its production scale. For this reason, it offers job vacancies based on the planned
				output. The household who is job seeker looks for a suitable position based on the
				corresponding salaries of these vacancies. Thus, a search-and-matching process is used to
				represent the interaction between CGPs and Households in this market. Specifically, the
				labor market is global with spatial frictions determined by commuting costs that arise if
				job seekers accept jobs outside their own region.</para>
		</sect2>
		<sect2>
			<title>Analysis of the model</title>
			<para>This section focuses on the analysis of the model. In general, there are three ingredients
				in this model: market, agent and activity. Markets do not act, because they have no
				intentions and cannot perform actions. However, they can provide some contexts for agents to
				act in. Agents always act within markets. They take some activities with different roles.
				Therefore, the analysis is concentrated on agents, which are involved in different markets
				and characterized by different actions.</para>
			<sect3>
				<title>Households</title>
				<para>The model consists of a large number of households, who are simultaneously taking the
					roles of buyers and workers. Households receive their income and determine how much to
					spend and how much to save. In general, the household makes some decisions with the
					related roles affecting the markets as follows.<orderedlist>
						<listitem>
							<para>Allocate budget on consumption and saving</para>
						</listitem>
						<listitem>
							<para>Choice of consumption goods</para>
						</listitem>
						<listitem>
							<para>Search for a job</para>
						</listitem>
						<listitem>
							<para>Acquire specific skills</para>
						</listitem>
					</orderedlist></para>
				<sect4>
					<title>Allocate budget on consumption and saving</title>
					<para>The household acting as the role of buyer (or consumer) sets once a month the consumption
						budget which is spent on the consumption goods market and consequently determines the
						remaining part which is saved.</para>
					<table frame="all">
						<title>The savings decision</title>
						<tgroup cols="5" align="center">
							<colspec colname="c1" colnum="1" colwidth="1.0*"/>
							<colspec colname="c2" colnum="2" colwidth="1.0*"/>
							<colspec colname="c3" colnum="3" colwidth="1.0*"/>
							<colspec colname="c4" colnum="4" colwidth="1.5*"/>
							<colspec colname="c5" colnum="5" colwidth="0.5*"/>
							<thead valign="middle">
								<row>
									<entry>Variable/Parameter</entry>
									<entry>Symbol</entry>
									<entry>Name (in the sim model)</entry>
									<entry>Description</entry>
									<entry>Value</entry>
								</row>
							</thead>
							<tbody valign="middle">
								<row>
									<entry>personal consumption budget</entry>
									<entry><emphasis role="italic">B<superscript>cons</superscript></emphasis></entry>
									<entry>consumptionBudget</entry>
									<entry>The consumer decides about the budget that he will spend for consumption</entry>
									<entry/>
								</row>
								<row>
									<entry>the available liquidity</entry>
									<entry><emphasis role="italic">Liq<superscript>Avail</superscript></emphasis></entry>
									<entry>cashOnHand</entry>
									<entry>The cash on hand that contains current income (i.e. labor income and dividends
										distributed by capital and consumption goods producers) and assets carried over
										from the previous period</entry>
									<entry/>
								</row>
								<row>
									<entry>mean income</entry>
									<entry><emphasis role="italic">Inc<superscript>Mean</superscript></emphasis></entry>
									<entry>meanIncome</entry>
									<entry>The mean individual (labor) income of a consumer over the last periods</entry>
									<entry/>
								</row>
								<row>
									<entry>the percentage of mean income</entry>
									<entry>&#x03a6;</entry>
									<entry>phi</entry>
									<entry>&#x03a6; &#x2264; 1 is the percentage of the mean income such that the consumer
										spends all cash on hand below that level</entry>
									<entry><emphasis role="italic">0.9</emphasis></entry>
								</row>
								<row>
									<entry>marginal saving propensity</entry>
									<entry>&#x3ba;</entry>
									<entry>savingPropensity</entry>
									<entry>0 &lt; &#x3ba; &lt; 1 is the saving
										propensity</entry>
									<entry><emphasis role="italic">0.1</emphasis></entry>
								</row>
							</tbody>
						</tgroup>
					</table>
					<para><emphasis role="bold">Algorithm:</emphasis> There exists a critical value &#x03a6;
						&#x2217; <emphasis role="italic">Inc<superscript>Mean</superscript></emphasis> of cash
						on hand to determine how much cash on hand will be spent for consumption in this month.
						When the available liquidity <emphasis role="italic"
							>Liq<superscript>Avail</superscript></emphasis> is below this critical value the whole
						cash on hand will be spent. Thus, the consumption budget <inlineequation>
							<math display="block" xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1998/Math/MathML">
								<mrow>
									<msup>
										<mi>B</mi>
										<mrow>
											<mi>c</mi>
											<mi>o</mi>
											<mi>n</mi>
											<mi>s</mi>
										</mrow>
									</msup>
									<mo>=</mo>
									<mi>L</mi>
									<mi>i</mi>
									<msup>
										<mi>q</mi>
										<mrow>
											<mi>A</mi>
											<mi>v</mi>
											<mi>a</mi>
											<mi>i</mi>
											<mi>l</mi>
										</mrow>
									</msup>
								</mrow>
							</math>
						</inlineequation>. In the opposite case the consumer will save a part of his cash on
						hand, so he sets his consumption budget according to the following consumption
						rule</para>
					<equation>
						<math display="block" xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1998/Math/MathML">
							<mrow>
								<msup>
									<mi>B</mi>
									<mrow>
										<mi>c</mi>
										<mi>o</mi>
										<mi>n</mi>
										<mi>s</mi>
									</mrow>
								</msup>
								<mo>=</mo>
								<mi>L</mi>
								<mi>i</mi>
								<msup>
									<mi>q</mi>
									<mrow>
										<mi>A</mi>
										<mi>v</mi>
										<mi>a</mi>
										<mi>i</mi>
										<mi>l</mi>
									</mrow>
								</msup>
								<mo>&#x2212;</mo>
								<mi>k</mi>
								<mo>&#x2217;</mo>
								<mrow>
									<mo>(</mo>
									<mrow>
										<mi>L</mi>
										<mi>i</mi>
										<msup>
											<mi>q</mi>
											<mrow>
												<mi>A</mi>
												<mi>v</mi>
												<mi>a</mi>
												<mi>i</mi>
												<mi>l</mi>
											</mrow>
										</msup>
										<mo>&#x2212;</mo>
										<mi>&#x03A6;</mi>
										<mo>&#x2217;</mo>
										<mi>I</mi>
										<mi>n</mi>
										<msup>
											<mi>c</mi>
											<mrow>
												<mi>M</mi>
												<mi>e</mi>
												<mi>a</mi>
												<mi>n</mi>
											</mrow>
										</msup>
									</mrow>
									<mo>)</mo>
								</mrow>
							</mrow>
						</math>
					</equation>
				</sect4>
				<sect4>
					<title>Choice of consumption goods</title>
					<para>The consumer purchases consumption goods according to his consumption budget. He splits
						the consumption budget into four equal shares, each of which is used for shopping per
						week. After determining the weekly budget, each consumer visits once a week to the mall
						in his region to buy goods. When visiting the mall he collects information about prices
						and quantities of different goods and then purchases goods according to his preference
						and available stocks of goods at posted prices. The model includes neither any kind of
						horizontal product differentiation, nor any kind of quality differentiation. Therefore,
						choice probabilities depend solely on prices.</para>
					<para>Consumers make their purchasing decisions based on the prices of different goods using a
						stochastic rule as described in a standard logit model. In the marketing literature it
						is standard to describe individual consumption decisions. This model represents the
						stochastic influence of factors not explicitly modeled on consumption decisions, see
						[Guadagni and Little 1983].</para>
					<table frame="all">
						<title>Selection of consumption goods</title>
						<tgroup cols="5" align="center">
							<colspec colname="c1" colnum="1" colwidth="1.0*"/>
							<colspec colname="c2" colnum="2" colwidth="1.0*"/>
							<colspec colname="c3" colnum="3" colwidth="1.0*"/>
							<colspec colname="c4" colnum="4" colwidth="1.5*"/>
							<colspec colname="c5" colnum="5" colwidth="0.5*"/>
							<thead valign="middle">
								<row>
									<entry>Variable/Parameter</entry>
									<entry>Symbol</entry>
									<entry>Name (in the sim model)</entry>
									<entry>Description</entry>
									<entry>Value</entry>
								</row>
							</thead>
							<tbody valign="middle">
								<row>
									<entry>the selection probability</entry>
									<entry><emphasis role="italic">Prob</emphasis></entry>
									<entry>selectionProbability</entry>
									<entry>The consumer decides which consumption good to buy on the basis of the selection
										probability of every consumption good sampled by him</entry>
									<entry/>
								</row>
								<row>
									<entry>available stocks of goods</entry>
									<entry><emphasis role="italic">G<subscript>week</subscript></emphasis></entry>
									<entry>availableProducts</entry>
									<entry>The consumption good whose quantity is positive at the attended mall will be sampled
										in week (of period)</entry>
									<entry/>
								</row>
								<row>
									<entry>the price of the consumption good</entry>
									<entry><emphasis role="italic">p<subscript>i</subscript></emphasis></entry>
									<entry>productSalesPrice</entry>
									<entry>The price of the consumption good i</entry>
									<entry/>
								</row>
								<row>
									<entry>the value of the consumption good</entry>
									<entry><emphasis role="italic">v(p<subscript>i</subscript>)</emphasis></entry>
									<entry>consumptionValue</entry>
									<entry>A function whose parameter is p<subscript>i</subscript> determines the subjective
										value of the consumption good i for consumer</entry>
									<entry><emphasis role="italic">-ln(p<subscript>i</subscript>)</emphasis></entry>
								</row>
								<row>
									<entry>the intensity of choice by consumer</entry>
									<entry>&#x03bb;<emphasis role="italic"><superscript>cons</superscript></emphasis></entry>
									<entry>intensityOfProductChoice</entry>
									<entry>The intensity of choice by consumer</entry>
									<entry><emphasis role="italic">8.5</emphasis></entry>
								</row>
							</tbody>
						</tgroup>
					</table>
					<para><emphasis role="bold">Algorithm:</emphasis> The decision of a consumer which consumption
						good to buy is random, where purchasing probabilities are based on the values he
						attaches to the different choices he is aware of. The consumer selects one consumption
						good i &#x2208; <emphasis role="italic">G<subscript>week</subscript></emphasis>, where
						the selection probability reads</para>
					<equation>
						<math display="block" xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1998/Math/MathML">
							<mrow>
								<mi>P</mi>
								<mi>r</mi>
								<mi>o</mi>
								<mi>b</mi>
								<mo>=</mo>
								<mfrac>
									<mrow>
										<mi>E</mi>
										<mi>x</mi>
										<mi>p</mi>
										<mrow>
											<mo>[</mo>
											<mrow>
												<msup>
													<mi>&#x03BB;</mi>
													<mrow>
														<mi>c</mi>
														<mi>o</mi>
														<mi>n</mi>
														<mi>s</mi>
													</mrow>
												</msup>
												<mo>&#x2217;</mo>
												<mi>v</mi>
												<mrow>
													<mo>(</mo>
													<mrow>
														<msub>
															<mi>p</mi>
															<mi>i</mi>
														</msub>
													</mrow>
													<mo>)</mo>
												</mrow>
											</mrow>
											<mo>]</mo>
										</mrow>
									</mrow>
									<mrow>
										<mstyle displaystyle="true">
											<msub>
												<mo>&#x2211;</mo>
												<mrow>
													<mi>i</mi>
													<mo>&#x2208;</mo>
													<msub>
														<mi>G</mi>
														<mrow>
															<mi>w</mi>
															<mi>e</mi>
															<mi>e</mi>
															<mi>k</mi>
														</mrow>
													</msub>
												</mrow>
											</msub>
											<mrow>
												<mi>E</mi>
												<mi>x</mi>
												<mi>p</mi>
												<mrow>
													<mo>[</mo>
													<mrow>
														<msup>
															<mi>&#x03BB;</mi>
															<mrow>
																<mi>c</mi>
																<mi>o</mi>
																<mi>n</mi>
																<mi>s</mi>
															</mrow>
														</msup>
														<mo>&#x2217;</mo>
														<mi>v</mi>
														<mrow>
															<mo>(</mo>
															<mrow>
																<msub>
																	<mi>p</mi>
																	<mi>i</mi>
																</msub>
															</mrow>
															<mo>)</mo>
														</mrow>
													</mrow>
													<mo>]</mo>
												</mrow>
											</mrow>
										</mstyle>
									</mrow>
								</mfrac>
							</mrow>
						</math>
					</equation>
					<para>Once the consumer has selected a consumption good he tries to spend the whole weekly
						budget for that consumption good if the stock at the mall is sufficiently large. In case
						the consumer cannot spend all his budget on the consumption good selected first, he has
						a single opportunity to select another good. If the budget is then not completely spent,
						the remaining amount is rolled over to the following week.</para>
				</sect4>
				<sect4>
					<title xml:id="section2">Search for a job</title>
					<para>On the labor market households who are job seekers search for jobs (there are the
						unemployed plus a certain fraction of on-the-job searchers). They see posted vacancies
						and apply to the ones if the wage offers exceed the current reservation wage of the job
						seeker. After applying they receive zero, one or more job offers and rank these offers
						with respect to the wage offer. In case the offered position is outside the home region
						of the job seeker, commuting costs are subtracted from the offered wage. If two or more
						wage offers are equal then these are ordered randomly. Job seekers accept at most one
						job with the highest offered wage and update their reservation wage which is the new
						wage. If job seekers are still unemployed they decrease their reservation wage.</para>
				</sect4>
				<sect4>
					<title>Acquire specific skills</title>
					<para>The household is characterized by a general skill level and specific skills. His general
						skill level is determined by outside factors like government and economic policy. The
						specific skills of workers are acquired on the job.</para>
					<table frame="all">
						<title>Specific skills (of workers) decision</title>
						<tgroup cols="5" align="center">
							<colspec colname="c1" colnum="1" colwidth="1.0*"/>
							<colspec colname="c2" colnum="2" colwidth="1.0*"/>
							<colspec colname="c3" colnum="3" colwidth="1.0*"/>
							<colspec colname="c4" colnum="4" colwidth="1.5*"/>
							<colspec colname="c5" colnum="5" colwidth="0.5*"/>
							<thead valign="middle">
								<row>
									<entry>Variable/Parameter</entry>
									<entry>Symbol</entry>
									<entry>Name (in the sim model)</entry>
									<entry>Description</entry>
									<entry>Value</entry>
								</row>
							</thead>
							<tbody valign="middle">
								<row>
									<entry>the average quality of the capital stock</entry>
									<entry><emphasis role="italic">A<subscript>i</subscript></emphasis></entry>
									<entry>averageQualityOfCapitalStock</entry>
									<entry>The average quality of the investment goods employed by CGP i</entry>
									<entry/>
								</row>
								<row>
									<entry>general skill level</entry>
									<entry><emphasis role="italic">b<superscript>gen</superscript></emphasis></entry>
									<entry>generalSkillLevel</entry>
									<entry>Every worker has a level of general skills <inlineequation>
											<math display="block" xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1998/Math/MathML">
												<mrow>
													<msup>
														<mi>b</mi>
														<mrow>
															<mi>g</mi>
															<mi>e</mi>
															<mi>n</mi>
														</mrow>
													</msup>
													<mo>&#x2208;</mo>
													<mrow>
														<mo>{</mo>
														<mrow>
															<mn>1,</mn>
															<mo>&#x2026;</mo>
															<mo>,</mo>
															<msubsup>
																<mi>b</mi>
																<mrow>
																	<mi>max</mi>
																</mrow>
																<mrow>
																	<mi>g</mi>
																	<mi>e</mi>
																	<mi>n</mi>
																</mrow>
															</msubsup>
														</mrow>
														<mo>}</mo>
													</mrow>
												</mrow>
											</math>
										</inlineequation></entry>
									<entry><emphasis role="italic">[1&#x2026;5]</emphasis></entry>
								</row>
								<row>
									<entry>specific skill level</entry>
									<entry><emphasis role="italic">b<subscript>t</subscript></emphasis></entry>
									<entry>specificSkillLevel</entry>
									<entry>Every worker has a level of specific skills in period t</entry>
									<entry/>
								</row>
								<row>
									<entry>increasing in the general skill level of the worker</entry>
									<entry>&#x03c7;<emphasis role="italic">(b<superscript>gen</superscript>)</emphasis></entry>
									<entry>chi</entry>
									<entry>A function whose parameter is b<superscript>gen</superscript> governs the speed of
										specific skill improvement</entry>
									<entry/>
								</row>
							</tbody>
						</tgroup>
					</table>
					<para><emphasis role="bold">Algorithm:</emphasis> While being employed each worker adjusts his
						specific skills to the average quality of the capital stock of his employer. The
						adjustment speed &#x03c7;<emphasis role="italic"
							>(b<superscript>gen</superscript>)</emphasis> depends positively on the general skill
						level of the worker.</para>
					<equation>
						<math display="block" xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1998/Math/MathML">
							<mrow>
								<msub>
									<mi>b</mi>
									<mrow>
										<mi>t</mi>
										<mo>+</mo>
										<mn>1</mn>
									</mrow>
								</msub>
								<mo>=</mo>
								<msub>
									<mi>b</mi>
									<mi>t</mi>
								</msub>
								<mo>+</mo>
								<mi>&#x03C7;</mi>
								<mrow>
									<mo>(</mo>
									<mrow>
										<msup>
											<mi>b</mi>
											<mrow>
												<mi>g</mi>
												<mi>e</mi>
												<mi>n</mi>
											</mrow>
										</msup>
									</mrow>
									<mo>)</mo>
								</mrow>
								<mo>&#x2217;</mo>
								<mrow>
									<mo>(</mo>
									<mrow>
										<msub>
											<mi>A</mi>
											<mi>i</mi>
										</msub>
										<mo>&#x2212;</mo>
										<msub>
											<mi>b</mi>
											<mi>t</mi>
										</msub>
									</mrow>
									<mo>)</mo>
								</mrow>
							</mrow>
						</math>
					</equation>
					<para>where the formula of the function &#x03c7;<emphasis role="italic"
								>(b<superscript>gen</superscript>)</emphasis> is</para>
					<equation>
						<math display="block" xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1998/Math/MathML">
							<mrow>
								<mi>&#x03C7;</mi>
								<mrow>
									<mo>(</mo>
									<mrow>
										<msup>
											<mi>b</mi>
											<mrow>
												<mi>g</mi>
												<mi>e</mi>
												<mi>n</mi>
											</mrow>
										</msup>
									</mrow>
									<mo>)</mo>
								</mrow>
								<mo>=</mo>
								<mn>1</mn>
								<mo>&#x2212;</mo>
								<msup>
									<mrow>
										<mn>0.5</mn>
									</mrow>
									<mrow>
										<mn>1</mn>
										<mo>/</mo>
										<mrow>
											<mo>(</mo>
											<mrow>
												<mn>20</mn>
												<mo>+</mo>
												<mn>0.25</mn>
												<mo>&#x2217;</mo>
												<mrow>
													<mo>(</mo>
													<mrow>
														<msup>
															<mi>b</mi>
															<mrow>
																<mi>g</mi>
																<mi>e</mi>
																<mi>n</mi>
															</mrow>
														</msup>
														<mo>&#x2212;</mo>
														<mn>1</mn>
													</mrow>
													<mo>)</mo>
												</mrow>
												<mo>&#x2217;</mo>
												<mrow>
													<mo>(</mo>
													<mrow>
														<mn>4</mn>
														<mo>&#x2212;</mo>
														<mn>20</mn>
													</mrow>
													<mo>)</mo>
												</mrow>
											</mrow>
											<mo>)</mo>
										</mrow>
									</mrow>
								</msup>
							</mrow>
						</math>
					</equation>
					<para>Brief interpretation: There are 5 general skill groups 1 to 5, where 1 is the lowest
						skill group and 5 is the group with the highest skills. A worker from skill group 1
						needs 20 months to close half of the gap between his specific skills and the technology
						of his employer, where a worker of skill group 5 needs only one fifth of that time,
						namely 4 months. Therefore, the higher the general skill level of a worker, the faster
						he acquires the specific skills associated with a given job.</para>
				</sect4>
			</sect3>
			<sect3>
				<title>Consumption goods producer (CGP)</title>
				<para>The CGP plays the role of buyer, seller and employer and makes a large number of decisions
					to influence the markets. Overall, it operates the sequence of events in the following way:<orderedlist>
						<listitem>
							<para>Product stock (optimal inventory) decision</para>
						</listitem>
						<listitem>
							<para>Production inputs (labor and capital) decision</para>
						</listitem>
						<listitem>
							<para>Investment (in investment goods) decision</para>
						</listitem>
						<listitem>
							<para>Employment (hiring and firing) decision</para>
						</listitem>
						<listitem>
							<para>Production (quantity) decision</para>
						</listitem>
						<listitem>
							<para>Pricing decision (which price to set)</para>
						</listitem>
						<listitem>
							<para>Dividend payment decision</para>
						</listitem>
					</orderedlist></para>
				<sect4>
					<title>Product stock (optimal inventory) decision</title>
					<para>The CGP keeps a stock of its products at every regional mall. It decides once a month
						whether the inventories at different malls need to be refilled in order to try to avoid
						the shortage of supplied goods and maximize the expected profit. To that end the CGP
						checks the current stock level reported by each mall it serves and determines an optimal
						stock level for each mall using a standard managerial method, which is based on a
						solution to the ""</para>
					<table frame="all">
						<title>Quantity choice</title>
						<tgroup cols="5" align="center">
							<colspec colname="c1" colnum="1" colwidth="1.0*"/>
							<colspec colname="c2" colnum="2" colwidth="1.0*"/>
							<colspec colname="c3" colnum="3" colwidth="1.0*"/>
							<colspec colname="c4" colnum="4" colwidth="1.5*"/>
							<colspec colname="c5" colnum="5" colwidth="0.5*"/>
							<thead valign="middle">
								<row>
									<entry>Variable/Parameter</entry>
									<entry>Symbol</entry>
									<entry>Name (in the sim model)</entry>
									<entry>Description</entry>
									<entry>Value</entry>
								</row>
							</thead>
							<tbody valign="middle">
								<row>
									<entry>the optimal stock level</entry>
									<entry><emphasis role="italic">Y</emphasis></entry>
									<entry>optimalStockLevel</entry>
									<entry>The CGP replenishes its stock at each mall in every period up to a given optimal
										stock level</entry>
									<entry/>
								</row>
								<row>
									<entry>the price of the consumption good</entry>
									<entry><emphasis role="italic">p<subscript>i</subscript></emphasis></entry>
									<entry>productSalesPrice</entry>
									<entry>The price of the consumption good i</entry>
									<entry/>
								</row>
								<row>
									<entry>the unit cost of production</entry>
									<entry><emphasis role="italic">c<subscript>t-1</subscript></emphasis></entry>
									<entry>unitCostOfProduction</entry>
									<entry>The unit cost of production in period t - 1 (the previous period)</entry>
									<entry/>
								</row>
								<row>
									<entry>holding cost</entry>
									<entry><emphasis role="italic">C<superscript>inv</superscript></emphasis></entry>
									<entry>holdingCost</entry>
									<entry>Holding cost per unit remaining at the mall for one period</entry>
									<entry><emphasis role="italic">0.1</emphasis></entry>
								</row>
								<row>
									<entry>monthly discount factor</entry>
									<entry>&#x03c1;</entry>
									<entry>rho</entry>
									<entry>The discount rate which takes into account the time value of money</entry>
									<entry><emphasis role="italic">0.95</emphasis></entry>
								</row>
								<row>
									<entry>the current stock level</entry>
									<entry><emphasis role="italic">SL</emphasis></entry>
									<entry>currentStockLevel</entry>
									<entry>The level of the stock which is checked at each mall</entry>
									<entry/>
								</row>
								<row>
									<entry>the desired replenishment quantity</entry>
									<entry><emphasis role="italic">D<subscript>r</subscript></emphasis></entry>
									<entry>replenishmentQuantity</entry>
									<entry>The desired replenishment quantity at the mall in region r</entry>
									<entry/>
								</row>
								<row>
									<entry>the sum of the orders</entry>
									<entry><emphasis role="italic">D<superscript>plan</superscript></emphasis></entry>
									<entry>sumOfOrders</entry>
									<entry>The sum of the planned delivery volumes for the malls</entry>
									<entry/>
								</row>
								<row>
									<entry>the planned output</entry>
									<entry><emphasis role="italic">Q<superscript>plan</superscript></emphasis></entry>
									<entry>plannedOutput</entry>
									<entry>The planned output that is used for the determination of the input factor
										needs</entry>
									<entry/>
								</row>
								<row>
									<entry>a linear combination</entry>
									<entry>&#x03be;</entry>
									<entry>xi</entry>
									<entry>For combining the planned current demand with weight xi and the historic demand with
										weight (1 - xi)</entry>
									<entry><emphasis role="italic">0.5</emphasis></entry>
								</row>
							</tbody>
						</tgroup>
					</table>
					<para>The CGP applies an optimal inventory policy to determine whether and how much to
						replenish inventory. The optimal inventory policy is the following:<itemizedlist>
							<listitem>
								<para>If the current stock level is greater than or equal to the optimal stock level <inlineequation>
										<math display="block" xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1998/Math/MathML">
											<mrow>
												<mi>S</mi>
												<mi>L</mi>
												<mo>&#x2265;</mo>
												<mi>Y</mi>
											</mrow>
										</math>
									</inlineequation>, the CGP does not need to replenish inventory <inlineequation>
										<math display="block" xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1998/Math/MathML">
											<mrow>
												<msub>
													<mi>D</mi>
													<mi>r</mi>
												</msub>
												<mtext>=</mtext>
												<mn>0</mn>
											</mrow>
										</math>
									</inlineequation>.</para>
							</listitem>
							<listitem>
								<para>If the current stock level is less than the optimal stock level <inlineequation>
										<math display="block" xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1998/Math/MathML">
											<mrow>
												<mi>S</mi>
												<mi>L</mi>
												<mo>&#x003C;</mo>
												<mi>Y</mi>
											</mrow>
										</math>
									</inlineequation>, the CGP needs to replenish inventory <inlineequation>
										<math display="block" xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1998/Math/MathML">
											<mrow>
												<msub>
													<mi>D</mi>
													<mi>r</mi>
												</msub>
												<mo>=</mo>
												<mi>Y</mi>
												<mo>&#x2212;</mo>
												<mi>S</mi>
												<mi>L</mi>
											</mrow>
										</math>
									</inlineequation>.</para>
							</listitem>
						</itemizedlist></para>
				</sect4>
				<sect4>
					<title>Production inputs (labor and capital) decision</title>
					<para>In this model for producing the homogenous consumption good two input factors are used,
						i.e. labor and capital. Based on the planned output the corresponding demand for capital
						and labor are determined.</para>
					<table frame="all">
						<title>Factor demand</title>
						<tgroup cols="5" align="center">
							<colspec colname="c1" colnum="1" colwidth="1.0*"/>
							<colspec colname="c2" colnum="2" colwidth="1.0*"/>
							<colspec colname="c3" colnum="3" colwidth="1.0*"/>
							<colspec colname="c4" colnum="4" colwidth="1.5*"/>
							<colspec colname="c5" colnum="5" colwidth="0.5*"/>
							<thead valign="middle">
								<row>
									<entry>Variable/Parameter</entry>
									<entry>Symbol</entry>
									<entry>Name (in the sim model)</entry>
									<entry>Description</entry>
									<entry>Value</entry>
								</row>
							</thead>
							<tbody valign="middle">
								<row>
									<entry>the planned output</entry>
									<entry><emphasis role="italic">Q<superscript>plan</superscript></emphasis></entry>
									<entry>plannedOutput</entry>
									<entry>The planned output that is used for the determination of the input factor
										needs</entry>
									<entry/>
								</row>
								<row>
									<entry>labor intensity of production</entry>
									<entry>&#x03b1;</entry>
									<entry>alpha</entry>
									<entry morerows="1">0 &lt; &#x03b1;, &#x03b2; and &#x03b1; + &#x03b2; = 1 &#x03b1;
										and &#x03b2; are the output elasticities of labor and capital</entry>
									<entry><emphasis role="italic">0.662</emphasis></entry>
								</row>
								<row>
									<entry>capital intensity of production</entry>
									<entry>&#x03b2;</entry>
									<entry>beta</entry>
									<entry><emphasis role="italic">0.338</emphasis></entry>
								</row>
								<row>
									<entry>the average quality of the capital stock</entry>
									<entry><emphasis role="italic">A<subscript>i</subscript></emphasis></entry>
									<entry>averageQualityOfCapitalStock</entry>
									<entry>The average quality of the investment goods employed by CGP i</entry>
									<entry/>
								</row>
								<row>
									<entry>the average level of specific skills of employees</entry>
									<entry><emphasis role="italic">B</emphasis></entry>
									<entry>averageSpecificSkillLevel</entry>
									<entry>The average level of specific skills of employees</entry>
									<entry/>
								</row>
								<row>
									<entry>labor input</entry>
									<entry><emphasis role="italic">L<superscript>plan</superscript></emphasis></entry>
									<entry>plannedLaborInput</entry>
									<entry>The planned labor force is directly related to the planned production
										quantity</entry>
									<entry/>
								</row>
								<row>
									<entry>capital input</entry>
									<entry><emphasis role="italic">K<superscript>plan</superscript></emphasis></entry>
									<entry>grossInvestment</entry>
									<entry>The planned capital stock is directly related to the planned production
										quantity</entry>
									<entry/>
								</row>
								<row>
									<entry>the price of the investment good</entry>
									<entry><emphasis role="italic">p<superscript>inv</superscript></emphasis></entry>
									<entry>investmentSalesPrice</entry>
									<entry>The price of the investment good</entry>
									<entry/>
								</row>
								<row>
									<entry>The average wage of employees</entry>
									<entry><emphasis role="italic">w<superscript>e</superscript></emphasis></entry>
									<entry>laborPrice</entry>
									<entry>The average wage of employees</entry>
									<entry/>
								</row>
							</tbody>
						</tgroup>
					</table>
					<para><emphasis role="bold">Algorithm:</emphasis> Two cases have to be considered for the
						factor demand determination:</para>
				</sect4>
				<sect4>
					<title>Investment (in investment goods) decision</title>
					<para>The existing capital stock of the CGP depreciates over time. Once there is a positive
						demand for investment goods, the CGP purchases the needed amount from the IGP thereby
						upgrading its capital stock.</para>
					<table frame="all">
						<title>Investment demand</title>
						<tgroup cols="5" align="center">
							<colspec colname="c1" colnum="1" colwidth="1.0*"/>
							<colspec colname="c2" colnum="2" colwidth="1.0*"/>
							<colspec colname="c3" colnum="3" colwidth="1.0*"/>
							<colspec colname="c4" colnum="4" colwidth="1.5*"/>
							<colspec colname="c5" colnum="5" colwidth="0.5*"/>
							<thead valign="middle">
								<row>
									<entry>Variable/Parameter</entry>
									<entry>Symbol</entry>
									<entry>Name (in the sim model)</entry>
									<entry>Description</entry>
									<entry>Value</entry>
								</row>
							</thead>
							<tbody valign="middle">
								<row>
									<entry>the gross investment</entry>
									<entry><emphasis role="italic">K<subscript>t</subscript></emphasis></entry>
									<entry>grossInvestment</entry>
									<entry>The stock of machines etc. needed for production</entry>
									<entry/>
								</row>
								<row>
									<entry>the new investment</entry>
									<entry><emphasis role="italic">I</emphasis></entry>
									<entry>newInvestment</entry>
									<entry>The CGP needs more investments in order to expand its production scale</entry>
									<entry/>
								</row>
								<row>
									<entry>the depreciation rate of capital</entry>
									<entry>&#x03b4;</entry>
									<entry>delta</entry>
									<entry>The depreciation rate of capital</entry>
									<entry><emphasis role="italic">0.01</emphasis></entry>
								</row>
							</tbody>
						</tgroup>
					</table>
					<para><emphasis role="bold">Algorithm:</emphasis> The capital stock of the CGP is updated as
						old capital is replaced by new investments.</para>
					<equation>
						<math display="block" xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1998/Math/MathML">
							<mrow>
								<msub>
									<mi>K</mi>
									<mrow>
										<mi>t</mi>
										<mo>+</mo>
										<mn>1</mn>
									</mrow>
								</msub>
								<mo>=</mo>
								<mrow>
									<mo>(</mo>
									<mrow>
										<mn>1</mn>
										<mo>&#x2212;</mo>
										<mi>&#x03B4;</mi>
									</mrow>
									<mo>)</mo>
								</mrow>
								<mo>&#x2217;</mo>
								<msub>
									<mi>K</mi>
									<mi>t</mi>
								</msub>
								<mo>+</mo>
								<mi>I</mi>
							</mrow>
						</math>
					</equation>
				</sect4>
				<sect4>
					<title>Employment (hiring and firing) decision</title>
					<para>After determining the required labor force during the calculation of planned production
						inputs, the CGP compares it to the existing labor force, and then decides to post
						vacancies or to dismiss workers depending on the difference between the required labor
						force and the existing labor force. In case a CGP has to downsize the labor force, it
						fires workers with the lowest general skill levels until the needed number of workers is
						reached.</para>
					<para>In another case, if a CGP has a positive demand for labor, vacancies are posted together
						with a wage offer. The incoming applications are ranked with respect to the general
						skill level. More specifically, applicants with higher general skill levels are ranked
						higher. If there exist two or more applicants who have the same general skill level,
						they are ranked by chance. The CGP sends as many job offers as it has vacancies to the
						highest ranked applicants. If the CGP then receives job acceptances from the applicants,
						it updates the number of employees and the number of vacancies. Otherwise there are
						still some vacancies and the CGP increases the offered wage.</para>
					<para>On the whole, together with the job search activities of Households (see <link
							linkend="section2">section 2.3.1.3</link>), </para>
					<para>a search-and-matching process is used to represent the interaction between CGPs and
						Households in this market.</para>
				</sect4>
				<sect4>
					<title>Production (quantity) decision</title>
					<para>The production technology is represented by a Cobb-Douglas type production function. In
						economics, the Cobb-Douglas functional form of production functions is widely used to
						represent the relationship of an output to inputs. In this model for producing the
						homogenous consumption good two input factors are used, i.e. labor and capital.</para>
					<table frame="all">
						<title>Factor demand</title>
						<tgroup cols="5" align="center">
							<colspec colname="c1" colnum="1" colwidth="1.0*"/>
							<colspec colname="c2" colnum="2" colwidth="1.0*"/>
							<colspec colname="c3" colnum="3" colwidth="1.0*"/>
							<colspec colname="c4" colnum="4" colwidth="1.5*"/>
							<colspec colname="c5" colnum="5" colwidth="0.5*"/>
							<thead valign="middle">
								<row>
									<entry>Variable/Parameter</entry>
									<entry>Symbol</entry>
									<entry>Name (in the sim model)</entry>
									<entry>Description</entry>
									<entry>Value</entry>
								</row>
							</thead>
							<tbody valign="middle">
								<row>
									<entry>the quantity of production</entry>
									<entry><emphasis role="italic">Q</emphasis></entry>
									<entry>producedQuantity</entry>
									<entry>The quantity of production</entry>
									<entry/>
								</row>
								<row>
									<entry>labor intensity of production</entry>
									<entry>&#x03b1;</entry>
									<entry>alpha</entry>
									<entry morerows="1">0 &lt; &#x03b1;, &#x03b2; and &#x03b1; + &#x03b2; = 1 &#x03b1; and
										&#x03b2; are the output elasticities of labor and capital</entry>
									<entry><emphasis role="italic">0.662</emphasis></entry>
								</row>
								<row>
									<entry>capital intensity of production</entry>
									<entry>&#x03b2;</entry>
									<entry>beta</entry>
									<entry><emphasis role="italic">0.338</emphasis></entry>
								</row>
								<row>
									<entry>the average quality of the capital stock</entry>
									<entry><emphasis role="italic">A<subscript>i</subscript></emphasis></entry>
									<entry>averageQualityOfCapitalStock</entry>
									<entry>The average quality of the investment goods employed by CGP i</entry>
									<entry/>
								</row>
								<row>
									<entry>the average level of specific skills of employees</entry>
									<entry><emphasis role="italic">B</emphasis></entry>
									<entry>averageSpecificSkillLevel</entry>
									<entry>The average level of specific skills of employees</entry>
									<entry/>
								</row>
								<row>
									<entry>labor input</entry>
									<entry><emphasis role="italic">L</emphasis></entry>
									<entry>plannedLaborInput</entry>
									<entry>The planned labor force is directly related to the planned production
										quantity</entry>
									<entry/>
								</row>
								<row>
									<entry>capital input</entry>
									<entry><emphasis role="italic">K</emphasis></entry>
									<entry>grossInvestment</entry>
									<entry>The planned capital stock is directly related to the planned production
										quantity</entry>
									<entry/>
								</row>
							</tbody>
						</tgroup>
					</table>
					<para><emphasis role="bold">Algorithm:</emphasis> The production quantity of a CGP is given
						by</para>
					<equation>
						<math display="block" xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1998/Math/MathML">
							<mrow>
								<mi>Q</mi>
								<mo>=</mo>
								<mi>min</mi>
								<mrow>
									<mo>[</mo>
									<mrow>
										<mi>B</mi>
										<mo>,</mo>
										<msub>
											<mi>A</mi>
											<mi>i</mi>
										</msub>
									</mrow>
									<mo>]</mo>
								</mrow>
								<mo>&#x2217;</mo>
								<msup>
									<mi>L</mi>
									<mi>&#x03B1;</mi>
								</msup>
								<mo>&#x2217;</mo>
								<msup>
									<mi>K</mi>
									<mi>&#x03B2;</mi>
								</msup>
							</mrow>
						</math>
					</equation>
					<para>where,</para>
					<para><inlineequation>
							<math display="block" xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1998/Math/MathML">
								<mrow>
									<mi>min</mi>
									<mrow>
										<mo>[</mo>
										<mrow>
											<mi>B</mi>
											<mo>,</mo>
											<msub>
												<mi>A</mi>
												<mi>i</mi>
											</msub>
										</mrow>
										<mo>]</mo>
									</mrow>
								</mrow>
							</math>
						</inlineequation>: Complementarity between <emphasis role="italic">B</emphasis> and
							<emphasis role="italic">A<subscript>i</subscript></emphasis>.</para>
					<para/>
				</sect4>
				<sect4>
					<title>Pricing decision (which price to set)</title>
					<para>The price of the consumption good produced by the CGP changes with the unit cost in
						production.</para>
					<table frame="all">
						<title>Pricing</title>
						<tgroup cols="5" align="center">
							<colspec colname="c1" colnum="1" colwidth="1.0*"/>
							<colspec colname="c2" colnum="2" colwidth="1.0*"/>
							<colspec colname="c3" colnum="3" colwidth="1.0*"/>
							<colspec colname="c4" colnum="4" colwidth="1.0*"/>
							<colspec colname="c5" colnum="5" colwidth="1.0*"/>
							<thead valign="middle">
								<row>
									<entry>Variable/Parameter</entry>
									<entry>Symbol</entry>
									<entry>Name (in the sim model)</entry>
									<entry>Description</entry>
									<entry>Value</entry>
								</row>
							</thead>
							<tbody valign="middle">
								<row>
									<entry>the price of the consumption good</entry>
									<entry><emphasis role="italic">p<subscript>i</subscript></emphasis></entry>
									<entry>productSalesPrice</entry>
									<entry>The price of the consumption good i</entry>
									<entry/>
								</row>
								<row>
									<entry>Mark-up factor</entry>
									<entry>&#x03bc;</entry>
									<entry>markUpFactor</entry>
									<entry>The difference between the cost of a product and its sales price</entry>
									<entry><emphasis role="italic">0.2</emphasis></entry>
								</row>
								<row>
									<entry>the unit cost of production</entry>
									<entry><emphasis role="italic">c<subscript>t-1</subscript></emphasis></entry>
									<entry>unitCostOfProduction</entry>
									<entry>The unit cost of production in period t - 1 (the previous period)</entry>
									<entry/>
								</row>
							</tbody>
						</tgroup>
					</table>
					<para><emphasis role="bold">Algorithm:</emphasis> The CGP sets the price of its product
						according to the standard rule</para>
					<equation>
						<math display="block" xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1998/Math/MathML">
							<mrow>
								<msub>
									<mi>p</mi>
									<mi>i</mi>
								</msub>
								<mo>=</mo>
								<mrow>
									<mo>(</mo>
									<mrow>
										<mn>1</mn>
										<mo>+</mo>
										<mi>&#x03BC;</mi>
									</mrow>
									<mo>)</mo>
								</mrow>
								<mo>&#x2217;</mo>
								<msub>
									<mi>c</mi>
									<mrow>
										<mi>t</mi>
										<mo>&#x2212;</mo>
										<mn>1</mn>
									</mrow>
								</msub>
							</mrow>
						</math>
					</equation>
				</sect4>
				<sect4>
					<title>Dividend payment decision</title>
					<para>At the end of every month CGPs have to check whether they are in a profitable position
						that households can receive dividends from them. The CGP pays dividends depending on its
						monthly realized profit and current balance of saving account according to a simple
						dividend policy.</para>
					<table frame="all">
						<title>Dividend payment decision</title>
						<tgroup cols="5" align="center">
							<colspec colname="c1" colnum="1" colwidth="1.0*"/>
							<colspec colname="c2" colnum="2" colwidth="1.0*"/>
							<colspec colname="c3" colnum="3" colwidth="1.0*"/>
							<colspec colname="c4" colnum="4" colwidth="1.5*"/>
							<colspec colname="c5" colnum="5" colwidth="0.5*"/>
							<thead valign="middle">
								<row>
									<entry>Variable/Parameter</entry>
									<entry>Symbol</entry>
									<entry>Name (in the sim model)</entry>
									<entry>Description</entry>
									<entry>Value</entry>
								</row>
							</thead>
							<tbody valign="middle">
								<row>
									<entry>the sales revenue</entry>
									<entry><emphasis role="italic">Rev<subscript>t</subscript></emphasis></entry>
									<entry>productSalesRevenue</entry>
									<entry>The sales revenue in period t</entry>
									<entry/>
								</row>
								<row>
									<entry>cost of production</entry>
									<entry><emphasis role="italic">C</emphasis></entry>
									<entry>costOfProduction</entry>
									<entry>The production cost</entry>
									<entry/>
								</row>
								<row>
									<entry>the monthly realized profit</entry>
									<entry><emphasis role="italic">Pro</emphasis></entry>
									<entry>monthlyRealizedProfit</entry>
									<entry>The monthly realized profit is the difference between the sales revenue and the
										production cost</entry>
									<entry><emphasis role="italic">Rev<subscript>t</subscript>-C</emphasis></entry>
								</row>
								<row>
									<entry>the current balance of saving account</entry>
									<entry><emphasis role="italic">Acc</emphasis></entry>
									<entry>currentBalanceOfSavingAccount</entry>
									<entry>The current balance of saving account</entry>
									<entry/>
								</row>
								<row>
									<entry>the dividends</entry>
									<entry><emphasis role="italic">Div</emphasis></entry>
									<entry>dividends</entry>
									<entry>The CGP pays dividends to all households</entry>
									<entry/>
								</row>
								<row>
									<entry>a fixed proportion</entry>
									<entry><emphasis role="italic">div</emphasis></entry>
									<entry>div</entry>
									<entry>The CGP pays a fixed proportion <inlineequation>
											<math display="block" xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1998/Math/MathML">
												<mrow>
													<mi>d</mi>
													<mi>i</mi>
													<mi>v</mi>
													<mo>&#x2208;</mo>
													<mrow>
														<mo>[</mo>
														<mrow>
															<mn>0,1</mn>
														</mrow>
														<mo>]</mo>
													</mrow>
												</mrow>
											</math>
										</inlineequation> of its profit as dividends to all households</entry>
									<entry><emphasis role="italic">0.9</emphasis></entry>
								</row>
							</tbody>
						</tgroup>
					</table>
					<para><emphasis role="bold">Algorithm:</emphasis> If the monthly realized profit of a CGP is
						not positive, the CGP pays no dividends and the losses are entered on the current
						balance of saving account. In case of positive profit, the CGP pays dividends based on a
						simple dividend policy that defines three kinds of dividend rates depending on the
						current balance of saving account. The rule states<orderedlist>
							<listitem>
								<para>If the balance is negative <inlineequation>
										<math display="block" xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1998/Math/MathML">
											<mrow>
												<mi>A</mi>
												<mi>c</mi>
												<mi>c</mi>
												<mo>&#x003C;</mo>
												<mn>0</mn>
											</mrow>
										</math>
									</inlineequation> and the debt is on a scale above the last monthly revenue <inlineequation>
										<math display="block" xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1998/Math/MathML">
											<mrow>
												<mrow>
													<mo>|</mo>
													<mrow>
														<mi>A</mi>
														<mi>c</mi>
														<mi>c</mi>
													</mrow>
													<mo>|</mo>
												</mrow>
												<mo>&#x003E;</mo>
												<mi>R</mi>
												<mi>e</mi>
												<msub>
													<mi>v</mi>
													<mrow>
														<mi>t</mi>
														<mo>&#x2212;</mo>
														<mn>1</mn>
													</mrow>
												</msub>
											</mrow>
										</math>
									</inlineequation>, the CGP pays no dividends <inlineequation>
										<math display="block" xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1998/Math/MathML">
											<mrow>
												<mi>D</mi>
												<mi>i</mi>
												<mi>v</mi>
												<mo>=</mo>
												<mn>0</mn>
											</mrow>
										</math>
									</inlineequation>.</para>
							</listitem>
							<listitem>
								<para>If the balance is positive <inlineequation>
										<math display="block" xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1998/Math/MathML">
											<mrow>
												<mi>A</mi>
												<mi>c</mi>
												<mi>c</mi>
												<mo>&#x003E;</mo>
												<mn>0</mn>
											</mrow>
										</math>
									</inlineequation> and savings are above the monthly revenue <inlineequation>
										<math display="block" xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1998/Math/MathML">
											<mrow>
												<mi>A</mi>
												<mi>c</mi>
												<mi>c</mi>
												<mo>&#x003E;</mo>
												<mi>R</mi>
												<mi>e</mi>
												<msub>
													<mi>v</mi>
													<mi>t</mi>
												</msub>
											</mrow>
										</math>
									</inlineequation>, the CGP disburses all profits as dividends <inlineequation>
										<math display="block" xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1998/Math/MathML">
											<mrow>
												<mi>D</mi>
												<mi>i</mi>
												<mi>v</mi>
												<mo>=</mo>
												<mi>P</mi>
												<mi>r</mi>
												<mi>o</mi>
											</mrow>
										</math>
									</inlineequation>.</para>
							</listitem>
							<listitem>
								<para>In the remaining case, if the balance is between these critical levels of the
									above two cases, the CGP pays out a fixed proportion of profits as dividends <inlineequation>
										<math display="block" xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1998/Math/MathML">
											<mrow>
												<mi>D</mi>
												<mi>i</mi>
												<mi>v</mi>
												<mo>=</mo>
												<mi>d</mi>
												<mi>i</mi>
												<mi>v</mi>
												<mo>&#x2217;</mo>
												<mi>P</mi>
												<mi>r</mi>
												<mi>o</mi>
											</mrow>
										</math>
									</inlineequation>.</para>
							</listitem>
						</orderedlist></para>
				</sect4>
			</sect3>
			<sect3>
				<title>Malls</title>
				<para>Mall is modeled as a passive agent in this model, so it cannot take decisions. This agent
					performs the selling role of CGP in the region. It keeps and receives consumption goods
					produced by CGPs, then sells them and collects every product sales revenue that is
					reported back to the corresponding CGP.</para>
			</sect3>
			<sect3>
				<title>Capital Goods Producer (IGP)</title>
				<para>In this model, the IGP is unique and acts globally. It only has one role and plays the
					role of seller on the investment goods market. It supplies investment goods infinitely to
					all CGPs. The investment good as a kind of productive factor of CGP has two properties,
					i.e. quality and price, which are increased by simple rules.<itemizedlist>
						<listitem>
							<para>The quality and price of the investment good increase over time due to
								technological change. The price varies with the quality.</para>
						</listitem>
						<listitem>
							<para>Every month the quality is increased by 5% with probability 10% where with
								probability 90% there is no change of quality.</para>
						</listitem>
					</itemizedlist></para>
				<para>Finally, in order to close the model, the monthly revenue of the IGP is uniformly
					distributed to all households.</para>
			</sect3>
		</sect2>
	</sect1>
	<sect1>
		<title>Reconstruction of the model in AOR Simulator</title>
		<para>This section deals with the</para>
		<sect2>
			<title>AOR Simulations Framework</title>
			<para>In this chapter, the concepts of AOR modeling and modeling methodologies will be
				introduced.</para>
			<para>An agent-based approach for the conceptual modeling of organizational information systems,
				called Agent-object-Relationship (AOR).</para>
			<para>A description language for agent-based simulations, </para>
		</sect2>
		<sect2>
			<title>Scenario model</title>
			<para>This part describes</para>
			<sect3>
				<title>Statistics</title>
				<para>Some valuable data for analysis and research are extracted from the variables of the
					model. Simulation statistics are generated while the simulation is running and appear on
					the panel in AOR Simulator.<itemizedlist>
						<listitem>
							<para><emphasis role="bold">outputLowSkillRegion</emphasis> type: Float</para>
							<para>description: Counts the total outputs in the low skill region.</para>
						</listitem>
						<listitem>
							<para><emphasis role="bold">outputHighSkillRegion</emphasis> type: Float</para>
							<para>description: Counts the total outputs in the high skill region.</para>
						</listitem>
					</itemizedlist></para>
			</sect3>
			<sect3>
				<title>DataTypes</title>
				<para>Because not all the attributes can be declared with the standard data types, the AOR
					framework allows defining the custom (that is, nonstandard) data type.</para>
				<sect4>
					<title>ComplexDataType</title>
					<para>This tag is used to define the new complex data type. It can have attributes. These
						complex data types can be used in the same way as the standard data types.<itemizedlist>
							<listitem>
								<para><emphasis role="bold">ProductInStock:</emphasis> Represents a product, which
									is offered by a CGP and stored at malls. It has some attributes as follows.<itemizedlist>
										<listitem>
											<para><emphasis role="bold">firmId</emphasis> type: Integer</para>
											<para>description: Holds the "identity" of the CGP agent, which provides the
												product.</para>
										</listitem>
										<listitem>
											<para><emphasis role="bold">price</emphasis> type: Float</para>
											<para>description: Holds the price of the product.</para>
										</listitem>
										<listitem>
											<para><emphasis role="bold">quantity</emphasis> type: Float</para>
											<para>description: Holds the amount of the product, which is sold at
												malls.</para>
										</listitem>
									</itemizedlist></para>
							</listitem>
							<listitem>
								<para><emphasis role="bold">ProductListItem:</emphasis> Represents a product, which
									can be sampled by consumers. The attributes can be summarized as follows.<itemizedlist>
										<listitem>
											<para><emphasis role="bold">firmId</emphasis> type: Integer</para>
											<para>description: Holds the "identity" of the CGP agent, which provides the
												product.</para>
										</listitem>
										<listitem>
											<para><emphasis role="bold">consumptionValue</emphasis> type: Float</para>
											<para>description: Holds the value of the product depending on the price of
												the product.</para>
										</listitem>
										<listitem>
											<para><emphasis role="bold">selectionProbability</emphasis> type: Float</para>
											<para>description: The consumer decides which product to buy with the selection
												probability that depends solely on the price.</para>
										</listitem>
									</itemizedlist></para>
							</listitem>
							<listitem>
								<para><emphasis role="bold">ProductDemandRecord:</emphasis> Represents the market demand of
									a product in a period. The attributes are given below.<itemizedlist>
										<listitem>
											<para><emphasis role="bold">mallId</emphasis> type: Integer</para>
											<para>description: Holds the "identity" of the mall agent.</para>
										</listitem>
										<listitem>
											<para><emphasis role="bold">demand</emphasis> type: Float</para>
											<para>description: Holds the sales volume of the product.</para>
										</listitem>
										<listitem>
											<para><emphasis role="bold">maximumDemand</emphasis> type: Float</para>
											<para>description: Holds the maximum volume of sales in all periods.</para>
										</listitem>
										<listitem>
											<para><emphasis role="bold">optimalStockLevel</emphasis> type: Float</para>
											<para>description: Holds an optimum order point for each mall.</para>
										</listitem>
									</itemizedlist></para>
							</listitem>
							<listitem>
								<para><emphasis role="bold">InventoryPosition:</emphasis> Represents the desired
									replenishment quantity for a mall. The attributes are as follows.<itemizedlist>
										<listitem>
											<para><emphasis role="bold">mallId</emphasis> type: Integer</para>
											<para>description: Holds the "identity" of the mall agent.</para>
										</listitem>
										<listitem>
											<para><emphasis role="bold">quantity</emphasis> type: Float</para>
											<para>description: Holds the desired replenishment quantity of the product for
												the mall.</para>
										</listitem>
										<listitem>
											<para><emphasis role="bold">adjustmentFactor</emphasis> type: Float</para>
											<para>description: Holds the ration for each mall.</para>
										</listitem>
									</itemizedlist></para>
							</listitem>
							<listitem>
								<para><emphasis role="bold">WorkerInFirm:</emphasis> Represents a household, who is
									employed. It has some attributes as follows.<itemizedlist>
										<listitem>
											<para><emphasis role="bold">householdId</emphasis> type: Integer</para>
											<para>description: Holds the "identity" of the household agent.</para>
										</listitem>
										<listitem>
											<para><emphasis role="bold">wage</emphasis> type: Float</para>
											<para>description: Holds the wage of the worker.</para>
										</listitem>
										<listitem>
											<para><emphasis role="bold">generalSkillLevel</emphasis> type: Integer</para>
											<para>description: Holds the general skill level of the worker.</para>
										</listitem>
										<listitem>
											<para><emphasis role="bold">specificSkillLevel</emphasis> type: Float</para>
											<para>description: Holds the specific skill level of the worker.</para>
										</listitem>
									</itemizedlist></para>
							</listitem>
							<listitem>
								<para><emphasis role="bold">JobApplicationRecord:</emphasis> Represents a job applicant, who
									needs to find a suitable position. The attributes can be summarized as follows.<itemizedlist>
										<listitem>
											<para><emphasis role="bold">householdId</emphasis> type: Integer</para>
											<para>description: Holds the "identity" of the household agent.</para>
										</listitem>
										<listitem>
											<para><emphasis role="bold">generalSkillLevel</emphasis> type: Integer</para>
											<para>description: Holds the general skill level of the applicant.</para>
										</listitem>
										<listitem>
											<para><emphasis role="bold">specificSkillLevel</emphasis> type: Float</para>
											<para>description: Holds the specific skill level of the applicant.</para>
										</listitem>
									</itemizedlist></para>
							</listitem>
							<listitem>
								<para><emphasis role="bold">JobOfferRecord:</emphasis> Represents a job offer, which is sent
									to qualified applicants. The attributes are given below.<itemizedlist>
										<listitem>
											<para><emphasis role="bold">firmId</emphasis> type: Integer</para>
											<para>description: Holds the "identity" of the CGP agent.</para>
										</listitem>
										<listitem>
											<para><emphasis role="bold">wageOffer</emphasis> type: Float</para>
											<para>description: The CGP posts vacancies including the wage offer.</para>
										</listitem>
										<listitem>
											<para><emphasis role="bold">netWageOffer</emphasis> type: Float</para>
											<para>description: The commuting costs are deducted from the wage
												offer.</para>
										</listitem>
									</itemizedlist></para>
							</listitem>
						</itemizedlist></para>
				</sect4>
			</sect3>
			<sect3>
				<title>EntityTypes</title>
				<para>This tag contains messages, events, agents.</para>
				<sect4>
					<title>MessageType</title>
					<para>Messages are used to communicate between the agents. Every message structure is difined
						seperately. There are ten message types, two of which have no attributes.<itemizedlist>
							<listitem>
								<para><emphasis role="bold">TellCurrentStockLevel:</emphasis> Sent by malls to tell
									the CGP about the current stock level. This message has one attribute including
									quantity, which holds the amount of the product.</para>
							</listitem>
							<listitem>
								<para><emphasis role="bold">TellSalesRevenue:</emphasis> Sent by malls to tell the
									CGP about the sales situation. This message has two attributes including revenue
									which holds the sales revenue, and quantity that holds the sales volume.</para>
							</listitem>
							<listitem>
								<para><emphasis role="bold">TellDismissal:</emphasis> Sent by CGPs. The household
									checks whether is fired or not. This message has no attributes.</para>
							</listitem>
							<listitem>
								<para><emphasis role="bold">TellVacancy:</emphasis> Sent by households. The CGP
									receives applications for vacancies. This message has two attributes which hold
									the general skill level and the specific skill level of the applicant.</para>
							</listitem>
							<listitem>
								<para><emphasis role="bold">JobOffer:</emphasis> Sent by CGPs to qualified applicants. This
									message has two attributes which store the offered wage and region where the CGP
									is located.</para>
							</listitem>
							<listitem>
								<para><emphasis role="bold">AcceptJob:</emphasis> Sent by households to accept the
									positions. This message has three attributes including wage, generalSkillLevel and
									specificSkillLevel.</para>
							</listitem>
							<listitem>
								<para><emphasis role="bold">ResignJob:</emphasis> Sent by households. Because the
									household is offered a better job, he resigned his position. This message has no
									attributes.</para>
							</listitem>
							<listitem>
								<para><emphasis role="bold">DeliverProduct:</emphasis> Sent by CGPs to deliver the
									ordered products to the mall. This message has one attribute containing quantity,
									that holds the delivery quantity.</para>
							</listitem>
							<listitem>
								<para><emphasis role="bold">TellWage:</emphasis> Sent by CGPs. Wage is paid to the worker.
									This message has two attributes which store the wage of the worker and region
									where the CGP is located.</para>
							</listitem>
							<listitem>
								<para><emphasis role="bold">TellSpecificSkillLevel:</emphasis> Sent by CGPs. The
									household checks whether his specific skill level needs to be updated or not. This
									message has one attribute including specificSkillLevel which holds the adjusted
									specific skill level.</para>
							</listitem>
						</itemizedlist></para>
				</sect4>
				<sect4>
					<title>ActionEventType</title>
					<para>Action events are used by agents, which want to perform some actions. There are ten
						action event types, six of which have no attributes.<itemizedlist>
							<listitem>
								<para><emphasis role="bold">BuyNewInvestment:</emphasis> If additional investments
									are needed the CGP performs the action of purchasing new investment goods from the
									IGP. This event has no attributes.</para>
							</listitem>
							<listitem>
								<para><emphasis role="bold">DismissWorker:</emphasis> If the CGP wants to decrease the
									incumbent workforce it performs the action of downsizing. This event has no
									attributes.</para>
							</listitem>
							<listitem>
								<para><emphasis role="bold">PostVacancyInformation:</emphasis> If additional workers
									are needed the CGP performs the action of posting vacancies. This event has two
									attributes including firmId which holds the "identity" of the CGP agent, and
									wageOffer that holds the offered wage for vacancies.</para>
							</listitem>
							<listitem>
								<para><emphasis role="bold">InFirstIterationOfferJob:</emphasis> After ranking the
									applicants, the CGP performs the action of offering the positions. This event has
									no attributes.</para>
							</listitem>
							<listitem>
								<para><emphasis role="bold">DistributeProduct:</emphasis> After production, the CGP
									performs the action of distributing the products. This event has no
									attributes.</para>
							</listitem>
							<listitem>
								<para><emphasis role="bold">PayWage:</emphasis> When the CGP updates its labor
									force, it performs the action of paying wages. This event has no
									attributes.</para>
							</listitem>
							<listitem>
								<para><emphasis role="bold">IncreaseSpecificSkillLevel:</emphasis> The CGP performs the
									action of adjusting the specific skills of its employees. This event has no
									attributes.</para>
							</listitem>
							<listitem>
								<para><emphasis role="bold">PayEqualShare:</emphasis> The IGP performs the action of
									distributing its revenue to all households. This event has one attribute including
									share, which holds equal shares of the revenue.</para>
							</listitem>
							<listitem>
								<para><emphasis role="bold">PayDividend:</emphasis> The CGP performs the action of paying
									dividends to all households. This event has one attribute containing dividend,
									that holds equal shares of the dividends.</para>
							</listitem>
							<listitem>
								<para><emphasis role="bold">SetNewPrice:</emphasis> Once the CGP needs to adjust the price
									of its product, it performs the action of updating the price. This event has one
									attribute which records the new price.</para>
							</listitem>
						</itemizedlist></para>
				</sect4>
				<sect4>
					<title>ExogenousEventType</title>
					<para>In the simulation, each step is seen as a day. A week consists of 6 steps and a month has
						24 steps. There are six exogenous events, which affect state variables whose values
						cannot be changed by actions of agents.<itemizedlist>
							<listitem>
								<para><emphasis role="bold">Init:</emphasis> This event happens at the beginning of
									the simulation (occurrenceTime="1") and occurs only once.</para>
							</listitem>
							<listitem>
								<para><emphasis role="bold">StartOfMonth:</emphasis> This event simulates at the
									beginning of every month (occurrenceTime="2") and occurs at every 24 steps during
									the running of the simulation.</para>
							</listitem>
							<listitem>
								<para><emphasis role="bold">AtWeeklyIndividualConsumption:</emphasis> This event
									triggers the consumption activities of households (occurrenceTime="3"). It is
									repeated every 6 steps, namely on a weekly basis.</para>
							</listitem>
							<listitem>
								<para><emphasis role="bold">EndFirstIterationLaborSupply:</emphasis> This event
									occurs when the first round of hiring activity ends (occurrenceTime="14"). It is
									repeated every 24 steps, namely on a monthly basis.</para>
							</listitem>
							<listitem>
								<para><emphasis role="bold">EndSecondIterationLaborSupply:</emphasis> This event
									happens at the end of the second iteration of hiring activity
									(occurrenceTime="23"). It is also repeated every 24 steps.</para>
							</listitem>
							<listitem>
								<para><emphasis role="bold">EndOfMonth:</emphasis> This event simulates at the end
									of every month (occurrenceTime="25") and occurs at every 24 steps in the
									simulation.</para>
							</listitem>
						</itemizedlist></para>
				</sect4>
				<sect4>
					<title>AgentType Household Agent</title>
					<para>An institutional agent consists of a number of internal agents that perceive events
						and perform actions on behalf of it, by playing certain roles.</para>
					<para>The agents involved in the implementation are listed and specified in the following
						sections.</para>
					<sect5>
						<title>Attributes</title>
						<para><emphasis role="bold">id</emphasis> is a integer variable which holds the "identity" of
							the Household agent.<itemizedlist>
								<listitem>
									<para><emphasis role="bold">region</emphasis> type: Integer</para>
									<para>description: The region, where the household is located.</para>
								</listitem>
								<listitem>
									<para><emphasis role="bold">firm</emphasis> type: Integer</para>
									<para>description: The CGP, which is the employer of a household.</para>
								</listitem>
								<listitem>
									<para><emphasis role="bold">lastFirm</emphasis> type: Integer</para>
									<para>description: If a household changes his job, the last job is
										recorded.</para>
								</listitem>
								<listitem>
									<para><emphasis role="bold">jobSeeker</emphasis> type: Boolean</para>
									<para>description: Determines whether a household is job seeker or not.</para>
								</listitem>
								<listitem>
									<para><emphasis role="bold">generalSkillLevel</emphasis> type: Integer</para>
								</listitem>
								<listitem>
									<para><emphasis role="bold">specificSkillLevel</emphasis> type: Float</para>
								</listitem>
								<listitem>
									<para><emphasis role="bold">currentWage</emphasis> type: Float</para>
								</listitem>
								<listitem>
									<para><emphasis role="bold">totalIncome</emphasis> type: Float</para>
								</listitem>
								<listitem>
									<para><emphasis role="bold">meanIncome</emphasis> type: Float</para>
								</listitem>
								<listitem>
									<para><emphasis role="bold">currentIncome</emphasis> type: Float</para>
								</listitem>
								<listitem>
									<para><emphasis role="bold">savingAccount</emphasis> type: Float</para>
								</listitem>
								<listitem>
									<para><emphasis role="bold">cashOnHand</emphasis> type: Float</para>
								</listitem>
								<listitem>
									<para><emphasis role="bold">consumptionBudget</emphasis> type: Float</para>
								</listitem>
								<listitem>
									<para><emphasis role="bold">weekConsumptionBudget</emphasis> type: Float</para>
								</listitem>
								<listitem>
									<para><emphasis role="bold">remainingConsumptionBudget</emphasis> type:
										Float</para>
								</listitem>
								<listitem>
									<para><emphasis role="bold">selectFirstProductId</emphasis> type: Integer</para>
								</listitem>
								<listitem>
									<para><emphasis role="bold">selectSecondProductId</emphasis> type: Integer</para>
								</listitem>
								<listitem>
									<para><emphasis role="bold">spendBudgetForFirstProduct</emphasis> type:
										Float</para>
								</listitem>
								<listitem>
									<para><emphasis role="bold">spendBudgetForSecondProduct</emphasis> type:
										Float</para>
								</listitem>
								<listitem>
									<para><emphasis role="bold">purchaseQuantityForFirstProduct</emphasis> type:
										Float</para>
								</listitem>
								<listitem>
									<para><emphasis role="bold">purchaseQuantityForSecondProduct</emphasis> type:
										Float</para>
								</listitem>
								<listitem>
									<para><emphasis role="bold">availableProducts</emphasis> type:
										ProductListItem</para>
								</listitem>
								<listitem>
									<para><emphasis role="bold">jobOffers</emphasis> type: JobOfferRecord</para>
								</listitem>
							</itemizedlist></para>
					</sect5>
					<sect5>
						<title>Functions</title>
						<para/>
					</sect5>
					<sect5>
						<title>ReactionRule</title>
						<para/>
					</sect5>
				</sect4>
				<sect4>
					<title/>
					<sect5>
						<title>Attributes</title>
						<para>a<itemizedlist>
								<listitem>
									<para><emphasis role="bold">region</emphasis> type: Integer</para>
									<para>description: The region, where the CGP is located.</para>
								</listitem>
								<listitem>
									<para><emphasis role="bold">productSalesPrice</emphasis> type: Float</para>
									<para>description: The price of the product.</para>
								</listitem>
								<listitem>
									<para><emphasis role="bold">productSalesRevenue</emphasis> type: Float</para>
									<para>description: The monthly realized sales revenue of a CGP.</para>
								</listitem>
								<listitem>
									<para><emphasis role="bold">productSalesQuantity</emphasis></para>
								</listitem>
								<listitem>
									<para><emphasis role="bold">grossInvestment</emphasis></para>
								</listitem>
								<listitem>
									<para><emphasis role="bold">physicalCapitalStock</emphasis></para>
								</listitem>
								<listitem>
									<para><emphasis role="bold">newInvestment</emphasis></para>
								</listitem>
								<listitem>
									<para><emphasis role="bold">totalQualityOfCapitalStock</emphasis> type:
										Float</para>
									<para>description: The productivity of capital stock of a CGP.</para>
								</listitem>
								<listitem>
									<para><emphasis role="bold">averageQualityOfCapitalStock</emphasis></para>
								</listitem>
								<listitem>
									<para><emphasis role="bold">producedQuantity</emphasis> type: Float</para>
									<para>description: The actual output of a CGP.</para>
								</listitem>
								<listitem>
									<para><emphasis role="bold">costOfProduction</emphasis></para>
								</listitem>
								<listitem>
									<para><emphasis role="bold">unitCostOfProduction</emphasis></para>
								</listitem>
								<listitem>
									<para><emphasis role="bold">monthlyRealizedProfit</emphasis> type: Float</para>
									<para>description: The monthly realized profit of a CGP.</para>
								</listitem>
								<listitem>
									<para><emphasis role="bold">currentBalanceOfSavingAccount</emphasis></para>
								</listitem>
								<listitem>
									<para><emphasis role="bold">equalDividend</emphasis></para>
								</listitem>
								<listitem>
									<para><emphasis role="bold">optimalStockLevel</emphasis></para>
								</listitem>
								<listitem>
									<para><emphasis role="bold">laborSupplyQuantity</emphasis> type: Integer</para>
									<para>description: The number of vacancies.</para>
								</listitem>
								<listitem>
									<para><emphasis role="bold">wageOffer</emphasis> type: Float</para>
									<para>description: The wage offer of a CGP.</para>
								</listitem>
								<listitem>
									<para><emphasis role="bold">lastFourProducedQuantities</emphasis> type:
										Float</para>
									<para>description: List of </para>
								</listitem>
								<listitem>
									<para><emphasis role="bold">productDemands</emphasis> type:
										ProductDemandRecord</para>
								</listitem>
								<listitem>
									<para><emphasis role="bold">inventoryPositions</emphasis> type:
										InventoryPosition</para>
								</listitem>
								<listitem>
									<para><emphasis role="bold">workersInFirm</emphasis> type: WorkerInFirm</para>
								</listitem>
								<listitem>
									<para><emphasis role="bold">dismissalsList</emphasis> type: WorkerInFirm</para>
								</listitem>
								<listitem>
									<para><emphasis role="bold">jobApplications</emphasis> type:
										JobApplicationRecord</para>
								</listitem>
							</itemizedlist></para>
					</sect5>
				</sect4>
			</sect3>
			<sect3>
				<title>EnvironmentRules</title>
				<sect4>
					<title>EnvironmentRule</title>
					<para>AtStartOfMonthDetermineEmployedWorkerAsJobSeeker_Rule. Household decides whether to
						search on the job or not.</para>
				</sect4>
			</sect3>
		</sect2>
	</sect1>
	<sect1>
		<title>Simulation results</title>
		<para>In the simulation presented here there are two regions, with 5 firms and 200 households in
			each region. There are five general skill levels, 1 being the lowest and 5 the highest. The
			general skill levels are distributed uniformly among workers. The stochastic technology
			improvement process is defined such that a fully efficient economy would grow at 6% per year
			on average. The simulation was conducted over 4,000 periods (days), that is roughly 17 years.
			The values chosen for the parameters are </para>
	</sect1>
	<sect1>
		<title>Conclusion</title>
		<para/>
	</sect1>
</article>
