<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="http://www.oasis-open.org/docbook/xml/5.0/rng/docbookxi.rng" schematypens="http://relaxng.org/ns/structure/1.0"?>
<chapter xmlns="http://docbook.org/ns/docbook" 
        xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude"
        xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" version="5.0">
	<title>Introduction</title>
	<para>So far agent-based modeling (ABM) is a powerful simulation modeling technique that has been
		extensively developed and well used in a lot of areas, because it can provide many effective
		methods to facilitate the research into the complex problems of different scientific fields.
		In ABM, a system is modeled as a collection of independent acting units called agents. Each
		agent is able to perceive things and make decisions based on a set of rules. The model which
		will be described in this paper used ABM to explore the fields of economics. It focuses on
		an economy to analyse how the effects of different spatial distributions of economic policy
		measures depend on spatial frictions in the labor market expressed as commuting costs of
		workers who are employed outside their home-region. The purpose of this paper is to remodel
		it as a multi-agent based simulation using the Agent-Object-Relationship (AOR) simulation
		technology that was developed by Prof. Dr. Gerd Wagner and other team members at the
		Brandenburg University of Technology.</para>
	<para>This thesis is organized as follows.<itemizedlist>
			<listitem>
				<para>At the beginning of chapter 2, it gives a brief introduction to the ACE
					methodology. Then a review of some ACE models are presented. In this part a
					baseline model, EOS baseline 6 and model of the minimal economy are selected and
					discussed, because these models are representative.</para>
			</listitem>
			<listitem>
				<para>Chapter 3 gives a general overview of the economic model. At first, the
					related background information of the model is introduced. Then the model
					structure and the general set-up are discussed in this part. After that, general
					description of the model is illustrated.</para>
			</listitem>
			<listitem>
				<para>Chapter 4 offers a detailed analysis of the model. All the features that are
					very important for reconstruction of the model are described. This chapter is
					divided into two parts. The first part shows clearly the activities of four
					types of agents with different roles within markets. In the second part the UML
					class diagram and BPMN model are used, in order that the model can be better
					understood.</para>
			</listitem>
			<listitem>
				<para>Chapter 5 presents the AOR simulation and the reconstructed model. For a
					start, it gives a brief introduction of the Agent-Object-Relationship
					simulation. Then the scenario specification is introduced.</para>
			</listitem>
			<listitem>
				<para>Chapter 6 lays out the simulation results in forms of graphical statistics
					which appear at simulation runtime on the panel in AOR simulator. In order to
					judge whether the reconstruction of the model is successful, it is necessary to
					compare the results of the reconstructed model with those of the original model.
					So, in this part, it gives the descriptions and comparisons of the simulation
					results between the reconstructed model and the original one.</para>
			</listitem>
			<listitem>
				<para>Chapter 7 gives an evaluation about the result of the model reconstruction.
					First of all, the possible reasons which trigger the differences of some results
					are analysed. Then according to the analysis result, it is proved that the
					reconstruction of the model is successful. Finally, the advantages and
					disadvantages of the AOR simulation technology are discussed.</para>
			</listitem>
			<listitem>
				<para>Chapter 8 summarizes the research results of the thesis.</para>
			</listitem>
		</itemizedlist></para>
</chapter>
