<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="http://www.oasis-open.org/docbook/xml/5.0/rng/docbookxi.rng" schematypens="http://relaxng.org/ns/structure/1.0"?>
<chapter xmlns="http://docbook.org/ns/docbook" 
        xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude"
        xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" version="5.0">
	<title>Related work</title>
	<para>In the real world, economies are complex systems consisting of many autonomous heterogeneous
		interacting agents that exhibit emergent properties at the aggregate level. The recent
		worldwide economic crisis has speeded up the revolution of the methodological foundations of
		macroeconomic theory. The debate has arisen as to the quest for microfoundation concerning
		the microfoundations of macroeconomics. In order to try to explain macroeconomic behavior,
		modern macroeconomics use the microfoundations approach to build aggregate models, typically
		in the form of dynamic stochastic general equilibrium (DSGE) models. Furthermore, these
		models are constructed on the basis of numerous restrictive unrealistic assumptions such as
		homogeneity of individuals, perfect rationlity, rational expectations, perfect ex-ante
		coordination in an equilibrium, etc. Indeed, these assumptions appear inconsistent with real
		world economic operation. However, unfortunately, the mainstream macroeconomics embodied in
		DSGE models was a poor guide to the origins of the economic crisis, and left its followers
		unprepared for the symptoms.</para>
	<para>In recent years another modeling methodology which has emerged at the same time as DSGE
		models is agent-based computational economics (ACE). In fact, In order to investigate and
		understand global regularities in economic processes, different real world issues such as
		asymmetric information, imperfect competition, strategic interaction, collective learning
		and multiple equilibria possibility should be taken into account. The ACE modeling approach
		featured by bounded rationality, endogenous out-of-equilibrium dynamics and direct
		interactions seems well suited to respond to these realities. It is used to study complex
		adaptive systems that are populated by many interacting agents with exogenously given
		behavioral rules. Every agent is defined as an individual actor that has some reasoning and
		decision-making abilities that guide his interaction with others. A major advantage of the
		ACE approach is that assumptions about the macro level are not particularly required. The
		phenomena of the macro level are endogenously emerging from micro assumptions.</para>
	<para>ACE models to macroeconomic studies can be grouped into two categories. The first category
		includes massive simulations of real economies. The EURACE project, as a representative of
		this type, models the European economy. The second category contains stylized models of
		basic economies. Until now there have been some ACE models. Some example models will be
		introduced in the following sections.</para>
	<section>
		<title>A Baseline Model</title>
		<para>Matthias Lengnick presents in his work a baseline agent-based macroeconomic model
			which belongs to the second category. The baseline model is defined as a simple minimal
			ACE model which is concerned with basic macroeconomic relations in a non-growth
			environment. The components of the model are only households and firms, both of which
			are described by simple, adaptive rules of behavior. In order to embody the non-growth
			environment, supposed that the number of households and firms is exogenously fixed. The
			model simulates a pure market economy where government and central bank are not
			considered. The economy has only one region where all households and firms are located.
			In the model, different interactions and decisions take place in different time
			intervals like a day or a month, for example, households buy consumption goods daily
			while recruiting activities of firms are carried out per month. In general, the minimal
			unit of time is a day. Each month is set to have 21 coherent days.</para>
		<para>Based on activities of households and firms, sum up, the baseline model consists of a
			consumption goods and a labor market. In the consumption goods market, transactions
			between households and firms are taking place daily. Consumption goods are produced by
			firms and sold to households. Different firms produce a homogeneous good. A crucial
			assumption is that households cannot buy consumption goods from any firm, but they are
			only able to establish business relations with 7 different firms, including their
			respective employer. By contrast, firms can have trading relations with any household.
			However, trading relationships between households and firms are unstable and allowed to
			change during the running of the simulation. In the labor market, for producing
			consumption goods only one input factor is used, that is labor, which is provided by the
			household. Once a firm needs more laborers to expand business, it has some vacancies for
			households. If a household is discontented with his present job or unemployed, he looks
			for a new job. In the following the main activities and decision processes of households
			and firms are listed according to the sequence of events.</para>
		<para>At the beginning of a month each firm checks once every month whether any of its
			properties such as the wage rate, the number of employees and the goods price have to be
			adjusted. The dicision whether the wage rate should be changed is based on past hiring
			status at this offered wage rate. The number of employees or the goods price is
			determined based on a comparison of the current stock level with the most recent demand.
			After that, households begin to find more beneficial trading partners in order that new
			partners can provide cheaper consumption goods than existing ones or satisfy the demand
			fully. If they find such a partner, the existing connection is removed and the new one
			is established. If a household is unemployed, he needs to look for a job. If a firm has
			vacancy and its offered wage rate is at least as high as the reservation wage of the
			household, the position is accepted. Otherwise, the household keeps searching for work.
			In another case, an employed household may consider changing jobs, if his current wage
			is less than reservation wage. Moreover, a household also has to decide about the budget
			that is spent for consumption and consequently determine how much to save.</para>
		<para>After the above events have been performed, households purchase consumption goods from
			their trading partners every day. Each household visits randomly one of his partners for
			consumption every time. If the inventories of the firm are high enough to satisfy his
			daily demand, the household buys consumption goods he needs. In the opposite case, the
			household has to visit randomly another trading partner to satisfy the remaining demand.
			Next, each firm produces consumption goods every day in order to replenish inventories
			in time.</para>
		<para>At the end of a month wages are paid to all workers. At the same time, the liquidity
			of the employer is reduced while the liquidity of each worker is raised. In cases of
			positive remaining liquidity, the firm pays dividends to all households. In some cases
			the firm has negative liquidity, because there are no banks in the model, supposed that
			households are required to pay the firm deficit. After that, households change their
			reservation wage based on their currently received labor income.</para>
		<para>There are several advantages to the baseline model. First, although the model is
			simple, it can already mimic a number of empirical facts. Second, the model follows the
			ACE approach rigorously. Third, this model, of course, can be modified to explore other
			research areas. At the same time, the baseline model also has some disadvantages. First,
			the model based on a non-growth environment cannot reflect economies in the real world.
			Second, it is unrealistic that the number of households and firms is fixed throughout
			the simulation. Third, in the model, there exist several restrictive unrealistic
			assumptions.</para>
	</section>
	<section>
		<title>EOS Baseline 6</title>
		<para>EOS (Economics via Object-oriented Simulation) is another ACE model which represents a
			complete economy. The aim of EOS is to develop a computational laboratory where
			economists can try out hypotheses in a predetermined environment and study economic
			policies. Baseline 1, as initial version of EOS, was implemented by Michael Adelson,
			Chris Rucinski and Cody Wang and offered a simple economy that consists of two types of
			agents, two kinds of goods and two markets. Over time, Baseline 1 has been improved and
			expanded repeatedly. So far, the latest version of EOS is Baseline 6 developed by
			Zhihong Xu.</para>
		<para>Baseline 4 was the latest version before Baseline 6 appeared. Its components are four
			types of agents (such as laborer, firm owner, farm and utility factory) and three kinds
			of goods (that is, labor, food and utility). Laborers are allotted a certain amount of
			labor at each step that they can sell to firms, and they can also buy foods and
			utilities on the open market with the money that they have earned. Firm owners own a
			farm or a utility factory. They take away the profits of their firms and then use them
			to purchase foods and utilities. Farms hire laborers to produce foods. They sell foods
			on the open market and then distribute the profits to their owners. Utility factories
			operate in a similar manner, but the difference is that they produce utilities instead
			of foods. Baseline 4 is a stable model. However, it has some weaknesses. For example,
			firstly, the functions that are used in the model are too complex. Secondly, the effects
			of money and wealth are not taken into account. Finally, in order to maximize stability,
			the model has a few arcane exceptional rules. For correcting these problems, Baseline 6
			was created.</para>
		<para>Baseline 6 contains four types of agents (such as laborer, necessity firm, enjoyment firm
			and capital firm), three kinds of goods (that is, necessity, enjoyment and capital) and
			four markets (like labor, necessity, enjoyment and capital market). Laborers are the
			only "humans" living in this economy, so they have to consume a sufficient quantity of
			necessity at each step, otherwise they will die. Before deciding to buy necessity and
			enjoyment, there are two things laborers need to do. One is to decide how much money to
			spend for consumption and how much to save, and the other is to divide consumption
			between necessity and enjoyment by using the utility function. After that, laborers
			announce the demand functions for necessity and enjoyment to the both markets. Every
			laborer has a checking account and a savings account. The purchases are charged to the
			checking account. If the current balance of the checking account is negative, the
			laborer has to either transfer money from his savings account to his checking account or
			take loans. Finally, if the current wage of a laborer is lower than unemployment
			benefit, the laborer decides to leave the firm and immediately changes his job.
			Necessity and enjoyment firms need labor and capital to produce their products. They
			each determine a new wage budget and post it to the labor market for hiring laborers.
			Every necessity or enjoyment firm maintains a capital stock which depreciates over time.
			If there is a positive demand for capital, the firm purchases the needed amount in the
			capital market thereby upgrading its capital stock. If a firm makes a loss, it can take
			a loan form the bank. In Baseline 6 capital firms are not completely modeled. It is
			temporarily considered that capital firms take only labor as input to produce capital
			and the capital price is fixed.</para>
		<para>Overall, Baseline 6 is a relatively complete model. It adds a few elements and
			functions to describe the authenticity and capability of the economy on the basis of
			Baseline 4. However, Baseline 6 still has some weaknesses. First, firms do not optimize
			the usage of production inputs. Second, the problem of unemployment is ruled out. Third,
			the investment decision of firms is simplistic. Fourth, capital firms are not completely
			modeled.</para>
	</section>
	<section>
		<title>Model of the Minimal Economy</title>
		<para>The third example for ACE model is a minimal economy model, which is developed by
			Christopher K. Chan and Ken Steiglitz. The components of the model are divided into two
			main categories: households and firms. More specifically, households are further
			subdivided into workers and firm owners. Meanwhile, firms comprise farms, tractor
			factories and retail banks. Besides, there are three kinds of goods in this economy,
			i.e., labor, food and tractors. Each household needs to use his income to buy foods.
			Workers provide labor for firms and get wages. They set the budget how much cash on hand
			goes on consumption and determine the remaining part which is saved. Their savings can
			be used for investment. An unemployed looks for a job only when the offered wage which
			is determined by the labor union is higher than his reservation wage or when his net
			assets are lower than a globally defined poverty level. Each firm owner has a firm. If
			his firm is profitable, the firm owner gets income from dividends of the firm. If the
			firm is on the verge of bankruptcy, the firm owner needs to find a job to make some
			money for rescuing his firm. Each firm has several shareholders besides an owner. It is
			under obligation to pay dividends to its shareholders. Farms produce foods by using
			labor and tractors, where tractors that can be considered as capital goods are produced
			by tractor factories. Then foods are sold to households. In the same way, tractor
			factories produce tractors and sell them in the tractor market. Banks are a crucial
			component of the model. They ensure the circulation of money in the minimal economy. In
			general, the model describes a closed minimal economic system that consists of workers,
			firm owners, farms, factories and banks.</para>
	</section>
</chapter>
