<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="http://www.oasis-open.org/docbook/xml/5.0/rng/docbookxi.rng" schematypens="http://relaxng.org/ns/structure/1.0"?>
<chapter xmlns="http://docbook.org/ns/docbook" 
        xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude"
        xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" version="5.0">
	<title>Related work</title>
	<para>In the real world, economies are complex systems consisting of many autonomous heterogeneous
		interacting agents that exhibit emergent properties at the aggregate level. The recent
		worldwide economic crisis has speeded up the revolution of the methodological foundations of
		macroeconomic theory. The debate has arisen as to the quest for microfoundation concerning
		the microfoundations of macroeconomics. In order to try to explain macroeconomic behavior,
		modern macroeconomics use the microfoundations approach to build aggregate models, typically
		in the form of dynamic stochastic general equilibrium (DSGE) models. Furthermore, these
		models are constructed on the basis of numerous restrictive unrealistic assumptions such as
		homogeneity of individuals, perfect rationlity, rational expectations, perfect ex-ante
		coordination in an equilibrium, etc. Indeed, these assumptions appear inconsistent with real
		world economic operation. However, unfortunately, the mainstream macroeconomics embodied in
		DSGE models was a poor guide to the origins of the economic crisis, and left its followers
		unprepared for the symptoms.</para>
	<para>In recent years another modeling methodology which has emerged at the same time as DSGE
		models is agent-based computational economics (ACE). In fact, In order to investigate and
		understand global regularities in economic processes, different real world issues such as
		asymmetric information, imperfect competition, strategic interaction, collective learning
		and multiple equilibria possibility should be taken into account. The ACE modeling approach
		featured by bounded rationality, endogenous out-of-equilibrium dynamics and direct
		interactions seems well suited to respond to these realities. It is used to study complex
		adaptive systems that are populated by many interacting agents with exogenously given
		behavioral rules. Every agent is defined as an individual actor that has some reasoning and
		decision-making abilities that guide his interaction with others. A major advantage of the
		ACE approach is that assumptions about the macro level are not particularly required. The
		phenomena of the macro level are endogenously emerging from micro assumptions.</para>
	<para>ACE models to macroeconomic studies can be grouped into two categories. The first category
		includes massive simulations of real economies. The EURACE project, as a representative of
		this type, models the European economy. The second category contains stylized models of
		basic economies. Matthias Lengnick presents in his work a baseline agent-based macroeconomic
		model which belongs to the second category. The baseline model is defined as a simple
		minimal ACE model which is concerned with basic macroeconomic relations in a non-growth
		environment. The components of the model are only households and firms, both of which are
		described by simple, adaptive rules of behavior. In this paper, another ACE model which is
		chosen for reconstruction belongs to the first category. In contrast with the baseline
		model, it is a complex system consisting of multiple interactive agents. This model is part
		of the EURACE project.</para>
</chapter>
